(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-02T22:47:54.358738",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のじゃーーー！
Nojaaa!
よいしょ
There we go.
あらら？メラメラ？あちちメラ！
Oh? Flaring up? Achichi Mela!
ホロライブアソビまわり隊ご利益担当の火消し、あちちめいあなのじゃー！
The firefighter in charge of blessings for Hololive Asobi Mawaritai, Achichi Meia, is here!
のじゃ
Noja.
ついにこの日が来てしまったのじゃ
Finally, this day has come, noja.
ホラーゲームがやってきましたのじゃ！のじゃー！
The horror game stream has finally arrived, noja! Nojaaa!
うん、緊張してるからお面つけてるのじゃ
Yeah, I'm wearing a mask because I'm nervous, noja.
ちょ、ホラーゲーム怖いらしい。怖いらしい。
Wait, apparently horror games are scary. Apparently they're scary.
でも、８番出口はホラーゲームの中じゃと怖くないらしいっていうのを聞く
But I hear that, as far as horror games go, Exit 8 isn't supposed to be that scary.
本当に事前情報１個も入れてない。何が起こるかも知らない。
I really haven't looked up any information beforehand. I don't even know what happens.
うん、何が起こるかも知らない。そんな怖くない？
Yeah, I don't know what happens. Is it really not that scary?
怖くない？たいして？
It's not scary? Not really?
え、怖くない？おぬしら８番出口見たことあるの？
Eh, it's not scary? Have you guys seen Exit 8 before?
怖い？怖くない？でも、わし知ってるよ。
Is it scary? Or not? But I know.
わし知ってるよ、それ。あのさ...
I know about that. You see...
あのさ、辛いの得意な人がさ、あのカレーの甘口をさ...
You know, when people who are good with spicy food say mild curry...
ちょっと辛いカレーの甘口をさ、辛くないっていうやつと一緒じゃろ？
...which is actually a bit spicy, isn't spicy at all. It's the same thing, right?
ホラーゲームではない？え、ホラーとは思えない？
It's not a horror game? Eh, you don't think of it as horror?
何？誰を信じればいいのじゃ、わしは？
What? Who am I supposed to believe?
わしは誰を信じればいい？違う？
Who should I believe? That's not it?
そんなじゃない、あ、ジャンルがホラーじゃない？
It's not like that? Oh, the genre isn't horror?
あ、ジャンルがホラーじゃないんじゃの？入門編？
Oh, so the genre isn't horror? An introductory level?
間違い探し？間違い探し？
Spot the difference? Spot the difference?
なるほど、わかったのじゃ。
I see, I get it now.
じゃ、間違い探しだと思ってやるのじゃ。
Then I'll play it thinking of it as a "spot the difference" game.
間違い探しだと思ってやるのじゃ。でも、ちょっとおぬしらにね、最初にね、謝っておきたいことが...
I'll play it thinking of it as spot the difference. But first, I have something I need to apologize to you all for...
あ、謝る部屋行くか。謝る部屋行くか。ちょ、謝る部屋行くのじゃ。
Oh, should I go to the apology room? Let's go to the apology room. Wait, I'm going to the apology room.
あ、後ろが、後ろが。ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、よいしょ。
Ah, the background, the background... Wait, wait, there we go.
ちょっと謝る部屋行くのじゃ。あの、あの、あの、記憶力自信なし。
I'm going to the apology room for a bit. Um, um, um... I have zero confidence in my memory.
記憶力に自信ないのじゃ。わし、記憶力に自信が本当にないのじゃ。
I have no confidence in my memory. I really have no confidence in my memory at all.
昨日食べたご飯すら覚えてない。
I don't even remember what I ate yesterday.
うん、あの、20回とか繰り返せば覚えるのじゃ。
Yeah, like, I'll remember it if I repeat it about 20 times.
GeoGuessrの道中覚えてるじゃろって言われると思うんじゃが、あれすっごい頑張って覚えたのじゃ。
People might say, "But you remembered the routes in GeoGuessr," but I had to work super hard to memorize those.
ん。
Hum.
あの、短期記憶、短期記憶自信なし。
Um, short-term memory... I have no confidence in my short-term memory.
短期記憶に本当に自信がないですのじゃ。
I really have no confidence in my short-term memory.
つまり？つまり？ちょっと、あの、間違い探しゲー、ガチ自信なし、ですのじゃ。
Meaning? Meaning? Um, I have absolutely no confidence in spot-the-difference games.
ガチ自信なし、ですのじゃ。
I have absolutely no confidence.
うん。ちょっと、そ、それだけ。それだけ。
Yeah. Just, um, that's all. That's all.
ちょっと、じ、事前に。事前にね。事前にね。自信なしですのじゃ。
Just, beforehand... Just to let you know beforehand, okay? I have no confidence.
よし、よし、よし、よし、よし、よし、よし。ちょっと。
Okay, okay, okay... Just a moment.
なんか、後から、後から、「あちちめら、記憶力なさすぎ」って、ワロタみたいに言われたら、
Because, if you say later on, "Achichi Mela has zero memory, lol,"
へこむから、へこむから、最初に謝っておくのじゃ。
I'll get depressed, so I'm apologizing in advance.
記憶力、自信なし！
No confidence in my memory!
結構違いわかりやすい？あ、なんか、すっごいわかりやすいならいけるのじゃ。
"Is the difference pretty easy to spot?" Oh, if it's super obvious, I can do it.
すっごいわかりやすいならいけるのじゃ。
If it's super obvious, I can do it.
長い夜になりそう？そ、そんな！そんな！
"It's going to be a long night?" N-No way! No way!
耐久？そんなむずいのじゃ？そんなむずいのじゃ？
"Endurance stream?" Is it really that hard? Is it that hard?
あ、そういえばさ、そういえばおぬしらさ、
Oh, by the way, speaking of which, you guys,
今日さ、ホロライブ公式からさ、ハロウィンボイス出たんだけど。
today, the Hololive official accounts released Halloween voice packs.
ハロウィンボイス出たじゃんけど、聴いた？知ってる？
The Halloween voice packs are out. Did you listen? Do you know about it?
ハロウィンボイス出たじゃんけど。
The Halloween voice packs are out.
ハロウィンボイス2026、もう手に入れてくれたのじゃ？
Have you already gotten the Halloween Voice 2026?
挨拶違った？あ、そう！あのね、デビュー前に撮ったのじゃん。
"The greeting was different?" Oh, yeah! You see, I recorded it before my debut.
デビュー前に撮ったから、デビュー前に撮ったからね、
Because I recorded it before my debut...
挨拶とかも違くてね。喋り方はそんな違くないかもって思うんじゃが。
Even the greeting was different. I don't think the way I talk is that different, though.
うん。デビューする前のわしが聴けるのじゃ。
Yes. You can hear me from before my debut.
ハロウィンボイスが出てるのじゃ。あの、公式Xで。
The Halloween voice pack is out. On the official X account.
うん、わしのTwitterでも宣伝してるから、聴いてほしいのじゃ。
Yeah, I promoted it on my Twitter too, so I'd like you to listen.
なんか、なんじゃっけ？えっとね、
It's like, what was it again? Let's see...
大罪？大罪じゃない。7つの甘罪。
Deadly sin? No, not deadly sin. Seven Sweet Sins.
7つの甘い罪みたいなのでコンセプトっぽくて。
It seems to be themed around something like seven sweet sins.
わしの罪、なんか、罪のテーマみたいのがあって、
My sin, like, there is a sin theme,
わしのテーマが色欲？色欲なのじゃ。甘罪？
and my theme is lust? It's lust. "Sweet sin"?
甘罪。
Sweet sin.
7つの甘罪。甘いに罪と書いて。
Seven sweet sins. Written as "sweet" and "sin".
うん。
Yeah.
そう。
Yes.
なんか、
Like...
うん、そう。大罪に沿ったテーマ。
Yeah, yes. A theme based on the deadly sins.
意外だった？
Was it unexpected?
なんか、あの、
Like, um...
なんで、なんかね、罪を選ぶみたいのをお任せにしたら、
For some reason, when I let them choose the sin for me,
罪を選ぶみたいのをお任せにしたのじゃ。「なんでもいいのじゃ」って言ったら、
when I left it up to them, saying, "Anything is fine,"
あの、色欲になったのじゃ。
it turned out to be lust.
うん。
Yeah.
配役不一致？
Mismatched casting?
わからんよ！わからんよ！
I don't know! I don't know!
聴いてみてから判断するのじゃ。サンプルがあるっぽいのじゃ。
Judge it after you listen to it. I think there is a sample.
サンプルがあるっぽいから、それを聴いてから判断するといいと思うのじゃ。
It seems like there's a sample, so I think you should listen to it before deciding.
なんか、コスプレしたよ。コスプレしたのじゃ。うん。
I did a cosplay. I cosplayed. Yes.
コスプレを、しましたのじゃ。
I did a cosplay.
うん。
Yes.
のじゃ。
Yes indeed.
うん。
Yes.
サンプルがね、ホームページから多分聴けるからね、
You can probably hear the sample from the homepage,
あの、配信終わったらね、サンプルを聴いてね、良いなと思ったらぜひゲットしてみてほしいのじゃ。
so after the stream, please listen to the sample and get it if you like it.
うむ。
Mm-hmm.
うん。
Yeah.
人間、色欲持ち上げすぎじゃない？欲の中の1つじゃろ？
"Don't humans overhype lust?" It's just one of the desires, right?
なんか人間って過度に色欲を持ち上げるイメージがありますのじゃ。なぜ？
I get the feeling that humans overhype lust. Why?
なぜなのじゃ？空気読みでも思ったんじゃが。
Why is that? I thought about it during the Kuuki Yomi stream too.
サラマンダーにはない感覚。
It's a feeling a salamander doesn't have.
うん。
Yeah.
意外な一面？確かに、意外な一面が見れるかも。のじゃ。
An unexpected side? True, you might see an unexpected side of me.
うん。
Yeah.
のじゃ。
Yes indeed.
よいしょ。宣伝したのじゃ。
Okay, there. I've promoted it.
宣伝したから、そろそろゲームの方を始めようかな。
Now that I've promoted it, let's start the game soon.
8番出口
Exit 8
始めようかなって思うんじゃが
I think I'll get started...
おぬしら、準備はいいかの？
Are you guys ready?
準備はどうかの？
How's your preparation going?
いい感じなのじゃ？
Is everything good to go?
じゃあ、ここから、えっと...
Well, from here, let's see...
「８番出口」っていうゲームで遊んでいこうと思うので！
I'll be playing a game called "The Exit 8"!
ゲームが見たくて、わしの姿が見たいおぬしらは、高評価するのじゃ！
If you want to watch the game and see me, make sure to hit that like button!
サラマンダーを高評価で育てるのじゃ！
Let's raise the Salamander with your likes!
おねがいしますなのじゃ！
Please do!
おねがいしますなのじゃ！お面取ってほしい人は高評価するのじゃ！
Please! If you want me to take off this mask, hit that like button!
した？しましたのじゃ？
Did you? Did you do it?
１０回？偶数はだめなのじゃ！偶数をしたらなくなっちゃうのじゃ！奇数回押してほしいのじゃ！
Ten times? Even numbers are no good! If you click an even number of times, it gets canceled! Click it an odd number of times!
よしよし！
Alright, alright!
じゃあ、育ててもらったところで、始めていこうと思いますのじゃ！
Now that I've been nurtured, I shall begin!
よいしょ！
Here we go!
のじゃ。
Noja.
よいしょ。のじゃ？
Here we go. Noja?
のじゃ。
Noja.
ちょっと待ての。ちょっと待ての。うん。ん？うん。
Wait a second. Wait a second. Yeah. Hmm? Yeah.
ん？音量が...
Hmm? Is it the volume?
のっている？
Is it working?
ジーって音聞こえる？ジーって音聞こえる？おぬしら。
Do you hear a buzzing sound? Do you hear that buzzing, everyone?
ジーって音のってる？ゲームの音なんじゃが。
Is that buzzing sound playing? It's the game's audio.
聞こえる？聞こえない？
Do you hear it? You don't?
なに？聞こえる人と聞こえない人がいる。これも異変なのじゃ？これも異変？
What? Some can hear it and some can't. Is this already an anomaly? An anomaly?!
よいしょ。
Let's see.
音量はどうじゃろか？このジャンジャンって音とかも。
How is the volume? Like this background hum as well.
歩いてみないとそこまでわかんない。よし。じゃあ。
I won't really know until I start walking. Alright, then.
やってみて判断するのじゃ！
Let's walk and find out!
聞こえた？ジーって音。
Did you hear it? That buzzing sound.
えっと、ん？どっちが前？
Let's see, hmm? Which way is forward?
さすがにあっちか。
Obviously that way.
ちっちゃい？
Is it too quiet?
これくらい。おっきい？
How's this? Is it too loud?
歩いてみて。
Let me try walking.
これくらい。これくらい。どう？
About this much? About this much. How is it?
最初お手本？
First round is the benchmark?
わかったのじゃ。
I got it.
これくらい？じゃあ、これくらいにしてみますのじゃ。
Around this level? Let's go with this level then.
よし、始めるのじゃ！えっとね、ルールは...
Alright, let's start! So, the rules are...
えっと、暗記系っぽいのじゃ。自信のない暗記系！
It seems to be a memory game. I'm terrible at memory games!
なんかこういう、広告とか。エイト歯科医院とか。
Like these posters. "Eight Dental Clinic," for instance.
あの、上のね、天井とか、床とか。いろんなものを見て。
Looking at the ceiling, the floor, and other things.
異変を見つけるらしいのじゃ。目。
And looking for anomalies, apparently. Eyes.
防犯カメラ。
Security camera.
覚える。覚える？何を？
Memorize them. Memorize? What?
え？もっとがんばったほうがいいのじゃ？従業員専用、従業員専用。
Wait, do I need to look closer? "Employees Only." "Employees Only."
分電盤室。
Distribution Board Room.
従業員専用。清掃員詰所。
Employees Only. Janitor Room.
消火栓。火の用心じゃ！
Fire hydrant. Watch out for fire!
そして、広告も覚える。防犯カメラ作動中！
And memorize the posters too. "Security Camera in Operation!"
これなに？MOVE FES、フェス。
What's this? "MOVE FES," a music festival.
んっと、メイクアップ。
Hmm, makeup art.
えっと、司法書士、相談。
Uh, judicial scrivener consultation.
えっと、これは、ドッグサロン、ドッグ。
And this one is a dog salon. Dogs.
アルバイト・パート大募集！
Part-time Job Recruitment!
時給は、１０００円。
The hourly wage is 1,000 yen.
東京って今、ここどこなんじゃろうな。
Since it's Tokyo, where exactly is this place anyway?
時給１０００円でいいのじゃ？この世界ではいいのじゃ？
Is 1,000 yen fine? Is it okay in this world?
エイト歯科医院、歯、歯医者は世界一多いっていう、コンビニより多いって聞くのじゃ。
"Eight Dental Clinic." I hear there are more dentist offices than convenience stores in Japan.
よし、行くのじゃ！
Alright, let's go!
走るもするっぽいじゃん。
Looks like I can run too.
絵も覚える？んー、たぶんオッケー！行って、行ってみるのじゃ！
Should I memorize the pictures too? Yeah, probably fine! Let's head inside!
禁煙。タバコ、タバコ。
"No Smoking." Smoking, smoking...
うん、うん、うん。点字ブロック。
Okay, tactile paving blocks.
左側通行だって、わかったのじゃ。KEEP LEFT。
It says "Keep Left." Got it. Keep Left.
行ってみるのじゃ。よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Let's go. Hup, hup, hup, hup.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Hup, hup, hup, hup.
のじゃ。監視カメラもあるのじゃ。
Noja. There are security cameras too.
よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ
Here we go, here we go, here we go.
よいしょ のじゃ
There we go.
あ、人がいる。
Oh, there's a person.
え、ね、人いたらだめ？
Wait, is it bad if there's someone?
人いたらだめなのじゃ？
Is it bad if there's a person here?
禁煙。
No smoking.
人いたら、人いへん？人は異変じゃない？
Wait, if there's a person, is that an anomaly? Isn't a person an anomaly?
一旦行ってみるか。
Let's keep going for now.
えっと、歯医者、歯医者。
Let's see, dentist, dentist...
え、これ順番とかある？
Wait, is there a specific order?
歯医者、パート、ドッグ...
Dentist, part-time job, dog...
司法書士、メイク...
judicial scrivener, makeup...
なんかそんな変わってない気がするのじゃ。
I don't think anything has changed.
んで、分...
And then, dist...
分電盤室。
Distribution board room.
分電盤室...
Distribution board room...
従業員専用。
Employees Only...
清掃員詰所、なんか全然普通、普通な気がする。
Janitor's room. Everything seems totally normal.
普通な気がする。消火栓。
It feels normal. Fire hydrant.
防犯カメラ...
Security camera...
セキュリティーカメラ。
Security camera.
特に何か変なとこない気がする。
I don't think there's anything strange.
変なとこない気がするよ、のじゃ。
I don't think there's anything weird here.
でもあんま細かいとこ言われたら分かんないのじゃ。
But if it's too detailed, I might not notice.
行くのじゃ。行くのじゃ！
I'll keep going. Let's go!
ね、自分の足音怖。
Wait, my own footsteps are scary.
自分の足音怖！
My own footsteps are scary!
ちら。
Peek...
え、何もいへん、いへんないへんな。
Wait, there's no anomaly. No anomaly!
余裕。
Easy peasy.
振り向く？
Turn around?
いへんない、いへんない、いへんない。
No anomalies, no anomalies, no anomalies.
左側通行。
Keep left.
さっ。
Quickly!
何もない。え、じゃあ1回で行けるのじゃ？
There's nothing. Wait, can I make it on the first try?
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Yoisho, yoisho.
ちら。
Peek...
ふんふんふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
まだ何も怖くないのじゃ。
I'm not scared at all yet.
あ、おじさん来た。
Oh, the middle-aged guy is here.
おじさんいるから異変じゃない？
Since there's a guy, is this an anomaly?
禁煙ある。禁煙あったのじゃ。
There's the "no smoking" sign. It's there.
出口8、あったのじゃ。
Exit 8, it's there.
歯医者、あったのじゃ。
Dentist poster, it's there.
えっと...
Let's see...
パート大募集もあったのじゃ。
The part-time recruitment is also there.
分電盤室もある。
And the distribution board room is here too.
ドッグオープンある。
The dog salon opening is there.
司法書士もあるのじゃ。
And the judicial scrivener is there too.
メイクアップアートもあったのじゃ。
The makeup art poster was there too.
ムーブフェスもあったのじゃ。
And Move Fes was there too.
防犯カメラのやつもあったのじゃ。
The security camera poster was there too.
部屋も3つ。従業員専用、清掃員詰所。
There are three rooms. Employees Only, Janitor's room...
消火栓。
Fire hydrant...
うん。
Yeah.
行けるのじゃ。
I can proceed.
禁煙。
No smoking.
左側通行。
Keep left.
あれ、なんか変なのがある？
Ah, wait, is there something weird?
ね、これ前なかったのじゃ。ね、0って書いてるよ。
Wait, this wasn't here before. Look, it says 0!
0番になってるのじゃ。
It turned into Exit 0!
異変を見逃さないこと。
Do not overlook any anomalies.
異変を見つけたらすぐに引き返すこと。
If you find anomalies, turn back immediately.
異変が見つからなかったら引き返さないこと。
If you don't find anomalies, do not turn back.
うん。
Okay.
これがスタート？これがスタートなのじゃ？
This is the start? Is this the start?
のじゃ、サンプルなのじゃ？
So that was just a sample?
見逃した？見逃した？
Did I miss something? Did I miss it?
気づかなかったのじゃー！
I didn't notice!
0番、南武公園。
Exit 0, Nanbu Park.
水清中学校。
Mizuse Junior High School.
よし、覚えるのじゃ。
Alright, I need to memorize this.
よし、覚えるのじゃ、米子寺、成平ビル。
Alright, I must memorize them. Yonago Temple, Narihira Bldg.
八本木交差点、よし。
Happongi Crossing. Got it.
行きますのじゃ。わしの...
I will go now. My...
始めるのじゃ。
Let's begin!
なんかこのね。
Somehow, this...
閉鎖空間が怖いんじゃよ。
closed-off space is scary.
あ、おじさん。
Oh, the middle-aged guy.
えっと...
Let's see...
禁煙、ノー・スモーキング、出口8、あるのじゃ。
No smoking, Exit 8, it's there.
おじさんも通ってる。
The guy is also walking past.
エイト歯科医院、8月8日オープン、木、日休み。
Eight Dental Clinic, opening August 8th, closed Thursdays and Sundays.
アルバイト、アルバイトOK。
Part-time job, part-time is okay.
分電盤室。
Distribution board room.
えっと、おじさん？
Let's see, the guy?
引き返す？何？
Turn back? What?
のじゃ、目が怖い？わし見れてない。
Wait, are his eyes scary? I can't see them.
これ進んだら怒られる？
If I keep going, will I get scolded?
これ進んだら怒られるのじゃ？
Will I get scolded if I proceed?
一旦進んでみるのじゃ。
Let's try proceeding for now.
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ。
Noja, noja, noja, noja.
ん？
Hmm?
行くのじゃ。
I'll keep going.
0になった！
It turned into 0!
ね、0になった。
Look, it turned into 0.
間違ってるってことなのじゃ。
That means I made a mistake.
0だったらだめってことって聞いた。
I heard that staying at 0 is bad.
もう一回やるのじゃ。
I'll try again.
ちょっとコメント欄見ないように頑張るのじゃ。
I'll try my best not to look at the comments.
1人で頑張ってみますのじゃ、一旦。8ね。
I'll try my best by myself for now. It was 8, right?
よし、よし、よし、よし、よし。
Alright, alright, alright!
8ね。
It was Exit 8, right?
おじさん！まずおじさんの顔見る...
The guy! First, let's look at his face...
と、とりあえず、止まるのじゃ。
F-first, let's stop.
止まってみるのじゃ。
Let's try stopping.
ゆっくりとね。
Slowly...
うん。
Yeah.
時間制限ないじゃろ？
There's no time limit, right?
おじさん、見せて。顔。
Mister, show me your face.
おじさん、真顔。
Mister has a blank face.
おじさん真顔じゃからいいんじゃない？
His face is blank, so is it fine?
おじさん真顔だからいいんじゃない？
His face is blank, so isn't it fine?
これ、わしでスルーしたらこれも変になる？
If I pass by him, will this also get weird?
これもまたダメ？
Is this also bad?
よし、よし、よし、よし。
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
エイト歯科医院。
Eight Dental Clinic.
木・日休みなんじゃ。
They're closed on Thursdays and Sundays.
時給1,000円。
Hourly wage of 1,000 yen.
10:00〜18:00、18:00〜22:00。
10:00 to 18:00, 18:00 to 22:00.
よくあるやつ。
The usual.
分電盤室。
Distribution Board Room.
ドッグサロン ズーイ。
Dog Salon Zui.
司法書士。
Scriveners.
ドッグサロン、司法書士。
Dog Salon, Scriveners.
監視カメラもあるのじゃ。
There's also a security camera.
えーっと、メイクアップ、MOVE FES。
Let's see, Makeup, Move Fes.
これ変わんないのじゃ。
This doesn't change.
防犯カメラ作動中！
Security camera in operation!
従業員専用。
Staff Only.
火の用心。
Beware of fire.
よし、よし、よし、よし、よし。
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
いくのじゃ。
Let's go.
これ異変ない気がするのじゃ。
I feel like there's no anomaly here.
わし的に。
Personally.
左側通行。
Keep left.
え？
Huh?
また０！
Zero again!
また０なのじゃ！
It's zero again!
なんかあったらしい。
There must have been something.
なんかあったらしい？
There must have been something?
ええー？
Eeeeh?
覚えゲーってむずいのじゃ。
Memory games are so hard.
むー、むーーー。
Mmm... Mmm...
もっかいやってみるのじゃ。
Let's try it again.
はい、おじさん来る。
Okay, the mister is coming.
出口８。
Exit 8.
ちょ、頑張って覚えるのじゃ。
Wait, I must try hard to remember.
20回やったら覚えるのじゃ、さすがに。
After 20 times, I will definitely remember.
禁煙。
No smoking.
出口８。
Exit 8.
ちょ、おじさんの顔もゆっくり見るのじゃ。
Wait, let's take a good look at the mister's face.
えー、エイト。
Let's see, Eight...
歯科医院。
Dental clinic.
おじさんの顔。
The mister's face...
おじさんの顔、オッケー。
Mister's face is okay.
天井と床も見るのじゃ。
Let's also look at the ceiling and floor.
えーっと、のじゃ、エイト歯科医院、バイト募集。
Let's see... Eight Dental Clinic, part-time job hiring.
天井、天井、天井。
Ceiling, ceiling, ceiling...
床、床、床。
Floor, floor, floor...
床も特に。
Nothing on the floor either.
何もない。
Nothing.
アルバイト、ズーイ。
Part-time job, Zui.
司法書士。
Scriveners.
メイクアップ、MOVE FES。
Makeup, Move Fes.
でお部屋が、分電盤室。
And the room is, Distribution Board Room.
従業員専用、清掃員詰所。
Staff Only, Janitor Room...
清掃員詰所、
Janitor Room,
消火栓。
Fire Hydrant.
振り返る。
Turn back.
地下広場。
Concourse.
地下広場があちら。
Concourse is over there.
The Concourse is over there.
ふん、ふん、ふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
のじゃ。
Yeah.
地下広場じゃダメ？
Is the Concourse not okay?
地下広場に偽物？
An anomaly in the Concourse?
一旦これでいってみますのじゃ。
Let's try going like this for now.
よし。
Okay.
左側通行ですのじゃ。
Keep left.
あ！
Ah!
ねえ、見て！
Hey, look!
ねえ、お主ら見て！
Hey, everyone, look!
お主ら見て、数字が！
Everyone, look! The number...
数字が1になった！
The number became 1!
今までずっと0だったのに！
Even though it was always 0 before!
すごいのじゃ！
Incredible!
これ進めってこと？
Does this mean go forward?
さっきまでがダメだったけど、今回は進めたってことなのじゃ？
It wasn't working until now, but this time I made progress?
やった！
Yes!
やった、やった、やった！これクリアと言っても過言ではないのじゃ！
We did it! It's no exaggeration to say we cleared it!
もうクリアしたと言っても過言ではない、このゲームの攻略法を見つけたのじゃ！
It's no exaggeration to say we've already cleared it! I found the trick!
よし、よし、よし、よし、このまま行くのじゃ。
Okay, okay, let's keep going like this.
この調子ですのじゃ。
Just like this.
異変全部見つけるのじゃ！
Let's find all the anomalies!
よし、よし、よし、よし、よし。
Okay, okay, okay...
全然怖くないじゃん。
It's not scary at all.
全然怖くないのじゃ。
わしこれくらいならいけるのじゃ。
I can handle this much.
出口８、禁煙、NO SMOKING。
Exit 8, No smoking.
おじさんの顔をゆっくり見たいから待っててあげよう。
I want to take a close look at the mister's face, so let's wait for him.
待っててあげよう。
Let's wait for him.
おじさん、顔見せて。
Mister, show me your face.
普通の顔。
Normal face.
エイト歯科医院。
Eight Dental Clinic.
オッケーなのじゃ。
That's okay.
うん。
Yeah.
アルバイト、オッケーなのじゃ。
Part-time job poster, okay.
ドッグサロンZUI、オッケーなのじゃ。
Dog Salon Zui, okay.
分電盤室、オッケーなのじゃ。
Distribution Board Room, okay.
司法書士もあったし。
There was also the Scriveners poster.
メイクアップもあったし、監視カメラもあるし。
There was Makeup too, and there's a security camera.
従業員専用もあるし。
There's Staff Only too.
MOVE FESもあったし、防犯カメラもあるのじゃ。
There's Move Fes too, and the security camera poster.
清掃員詰所もある。
There's also the Janitor Room.
消火栓もある、火の用心じゃ。後ろを向く。
There's a fire hydrant too, beware of fire. Let's turn back.
引き返せだって！ねえ見てお主ら、お主ら危ないって！
It says "Turn back"! Hey, look, everyone! It says danger!
お主ら、お主ら、お主ら、わしみっけ、わしみつけたのじゃ！異変見つけたのじゃ！
Everyone, I found it, I found it! I found an anomaly!
異変なのじゃ、異変なのじゃ！
It's an anomaly!
「引き返せ」って書いてる！わしわかる！
It says "Turn back"! I understand!
引き返すのじゃ。
Turn back!
後ずさり。
Backing away...
追いかけられたら嫌じゃからね。
Because I don't want to get chased.
おじさん、スマホ見てる？
Is the man looking at his phone?
なに？これ怖い？
What? Is this scary?
これ怖いやつ？
Is this a scary one?
真ん中で立ち止まりスマホはね、駄目って聞いたことあるのじゃ。
I've heard you shouldn't stop in the middle of the path to look at your phone.
しかも点字ブロックの上。
And on top of the tactile paving, too.
炎上しちゃうのじゃ、おじさん。
You're going to get canceled online, mister.
おじさん、点字ブロックの上で止まったらね、今の時代じゃあね、炎上しちゃうから危ないのじゃ。
If you stop on the tactile paving in this day and age, you'll get canceled. It's risky.
気の用心じゃ。
Be careful!
「２」、あ、ね、「２」になった！「２」になったのじゃ！「２」になったのじゃ！
"2"! Oh! It became 2! It became 2!
「２」、「２」だよ「２」！
2, it's 2! 2!
１の次！
After 1!
いけるのじゃ！
I can do this!
この調子で、え、怖くないのじゃ、怖くないのじゃ。
At this rate... Wait, it's not scary! It's not scary!
監視カメラ。
A security camera.
え、わしホラゲーいけるかも。
Wait, I might actually be good at horror games.
わしホラゲーの神になる可能性あり。
I might become the god of horror games.
おじさん。
Mister.
よし、しっかりと見させていただきますのじゃ。
Alright, I will keep a close eye on everything.
禁煙オッケー？
No smoking, okay?
おじさんオッケー？
Is the mister okay?
うん。
Yeah.
おじさん？
Mister?
うん。
Yeah.
おじさんのお顔見せてほしいのじゃ。
I want to see the mister's face.
普通の顔なのじゃ。
It's a normal face.
オープン、オープン、オープンじゃ？
Open, open... Is it open?
アルバイトのじゃ、アルバイトのじゃ？
Part-time job? Part-time job?
分電盤室のじゃ。
Distribution Board Room.
ドッグ、ドッグ「ZUI」？
Dog... Dog Salon ZUI?
司法書士？
Scrivener?
えっと、えっと、
Let's see...
メイクアップアートのじゃ？
Makeup Art?
「MOVE FES」、え、全部あるよ、お部屋も３つ。
Move Fes... Everything is here, and three rooms as well.
従業員専用、
Staff Only...
清掃員、清掃員詰所？
Janitor... Janitor's Office?
消火栓。
Fire hydrant.
防犯カメラ作動中、セキュリティカメラ。
Security camera in operation... Security camera.
防犯カメラもここにある。
There's a security camera here too.
ある。
It's there.
地下広場、え、何もない！
Concourse... Wait, there's nothing!
何もない、異変なし！
Nothing. No anomalies!
異変なし。
No anomalies.
チェックして、
Checking...
問題なし、あ、でも一応振り返るのか。
No problems. Oh, but I should look back just in case.
振り返り、異変なし！
Looking back... No anomalies!
なしですのじゃ！
None!
進むのじゃ！
Moving forward!
え、これもうRTAなんじゃないの？
Wait, isn't this already an RTA speedrun?
「３」だ！ね、「３」！「３」なのじゃ！「３」なのじゃ！
It's 3! 3! It became 3! It became 3!
ね、「３」、「３」になってる！
"3"! It's 3!
「３」になっているということは、正解ってこと！
Being at 3 means I got it right!
おおー！
Ooh!
わしのプレイスキルにおぬしらきっと今恐れおののいてるんじゃないの？
Aren't you all trembling in fear at my gaming skills right now?
なかなかの、なかなかの記憶力なのじゃ。
My memory is pretty, pretty good.
うわ、謝罪しなくてよかったのか、これ。
Wow, did I not need to apologize for this?
これ謝罪しなくてよかったかもなのじゃ。
I guess I didn't need to apologize.
冒頭の謝罪いらなかったのじゃ。
The apology at the beginning was unnecessary.
のじゃ。
Indeed.
行くのじゃ。
Let's go.
ふんふんふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
ちら。
Glance.
出口８。
Exit 8.
おじさんのこと見ててあげる。
I'll keep an eye on the mister.
禁煙、ノースモーキングオッケー？
No smoking... "No Smoking", okay?
えっと、エイト歯科医院オッケー？
Let's see... Eight Dental Clinic, okay?
おじさんお顔見せて。
Mister, show me your face.
おじさん、おじさん普通なのじゃ。
Mister... Mister is normal.
変わり映えしない日々、わしとおじさん。
Unchanging days, just me and the mister.
うん。
Yeah.
オープン、アルバイト大募集？
Open... "Part-Time Job Recruitment"?
オッケー、分電盤室オッケー？
Okay... Distribution Board Room, okay?
「ZUI」オッケー？
"ZUI", okay?
司法書士オッケー？
Scrivener, okay?
メイクアップアートオッケー？
Makeup Art, okay?
え、異変なくてワロタ。
Wow, there are no anomalies, lol.
従業員専用、清掃員詰所。
Staff Only... Janitor's Office.
えっと、
Let's see...
え！ね、目動いてる！目動いてる！目、目、目、目、目！目動いてるのじゃ！
Ah! Look, the eyes are moving! The eyes are moving! The eyes, eyes, eyes!
目、目、目、目、目！目動いてるのじゃ！
The eyes are moving!
ひっ！
Eek!
なに？
What?
もう。
Oh, come on!
もう！
Seriously!
え、これ異変、これ異変です！
Wait, this is an anomaly! This is definitely an anomaly!
これ絶対に異変ですのじゃ！
This is absolutely an anomaly!
ええー！
What?!
なに？
What is it?
ハイテクな広告。
A high-tech poster.
ハイテクな広告、わしも出したい！
A high-tech poster, I want to put one up too!
ね、わしも、わしも目動く広告出したい！
I want to put up a poster with moving eyes too!
わしも動く広告出したいのじゃ、あ、秋葉原駅で。
I want to put up a moving poster at Akihabara Station!
秋葉原駅で今、遊びまわりたいの動く広告が出てますのじゃ！
There's a moving poster of me up at Akihabara Station right now!
「４」。
4.
え、合ってたっぽい。
Wait, seems like I was right.
合ってたっぽい。
I was right.
え、凄くない？わし凄い、わし凄い。
Wait, isn't that amazing? I'm amazing, I'm so amazing!
ね、わし凄いよ、ね、わし凄い！
I'm amazing! I'm really amazing!
順調すぎて、
This is going so well...
ワロタ。
...lol.
順調じゃん。
It's going so smoothly.
うん。
Yeah.
これいけるのじゃ。
I can do this.
ごめん、おぬしら。
Sorry, everyone.
今日、わしと長い時間一緒に配信で過ごしたかったおぬしら、ガチごめんなのじゃ。
If you wanted to spend a long time with me on stream today, I'm really sorry.
これ、秒ですのじゃ。
This is going to be over in seconds.
記憶力の神こと、
The God of Memory...
わし、あちちめら。
...is me, Achichimera!
え、謝罪しなきゃよかったのじゃ。
I really shouldn't have apologized.
危なかったら走るのをやったほうがいい？あ、走るとかもあるのじゃ？
If it's dangerous, I should run? Oh, there's a running feature?
了解なのじゃ。
Understood.
で、こっち、あっち。
And here, over there.
禁煙。No Smoking？
No smoking. "No Smoking"?
えーっと、歯科？えーっと、歯科？
Let's see, a dental clinic? Let's see, a dental clinic?
アルバイト？
Part-time job?
おじさん、オッケー。
Mister, okay.
オッケー？おじさんオッケー？
Okay? Is the mister okay?
おじさんオッケー？
Is the mister okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Distribution board room, okay?
出口8オッケー？
Exit 8, okay?
アルバイトオッケー？
Part-time job poster, okay?
ドッグサロンZUIオッケー？
Dog Salon Zui, okay?
えー、司法書士、オッケー。
Uh, judicial scrivener, okay.
んっと、メイクアップアーティスト、オッケー。
Hmm, make-up artist, okay.
ムーブフェス！
Move Fes!
あ、ねえ、動かない広告。
Oh, look, a poster that doesn't move.
安心感ありますのじゃ！安心感ある。
It gives me a sense of security! Truly reassuring.
防犯カメラ作動中。防犯カメラある、防犯カメラもある。
Security camera in operation. The security camera is there, indeed.
従業員専用ある。
The "Staff Only" door is there.
ある！清掃員詰所ある。
It is! The janitor room is there.
え？なくない異変。
Huh? Is there no anomaly?
消火栓、火の用心じゃ？
Fire hydrant, beware of fire?
火の用心じゃ？
Beware of fire?
異変ないのじゃ。異変ないのじゃ。
There are no anomalies. No anomalies.
え、異変ないのじゃ？
Eh, there really are no anomalies?
行くのじゃ！
Let's go!
行けるのじゃ、行けるのじゃ、行けるのじゃ！
I can make it, I can make it!
ゴー！え、ゴーだよ、ゴー。
Go! Yeah, it's a go, go!
ゴーじゃよ、ゴー。ゴーじゃよ。ゴーってことはゴーってことなのじゃ。
Go indeed, go. It's a go. If it's a go, it means I should go!
あと3つじゃ。え、え、え、え？
Just 3 more. Eh, eh, eh, eh?
秒で終わるのじゃ。秒で終わるのじゃ。わし、わしすごい。
I'll finish this in a second. I'm amazing.
わしすごいかも。え、わしこれからホラーゲーマーになろうかな。
Maybe I'm actually amazing. Should I become a horror gamer?
わしこれから間違い探し記憶力系ホラーゲーマーになろうかな。わしこれで覇権取るのじゃ。
Should I become a spot-the-difference memory-based horror gamer? I'll rule the scene with this!
あちちめら、と言えば、あちちめらの代名詞。
Speaking of Achichimera, her signature style is...
ホラーゲーム。謎、謎探し系のホラーゲーマー。
Horror games. A mystery/spot-the-difference horror gamer.
うわあ、すごいのじゃ。わしの新しい一面がお主らに。
Wow, this is great. You're all seeing a new side of me.
ちら。おじさん来た。よしよしよし。よしよしよし。
Peek. The mister is here. Good, good, good. Good, good, good.
禁煙。No Smokingオッケー？No Smokingオッケー？
No smoking. "No Smoking" is okay? "No Smoking" is okay?
出口8オッケー？おじさん見るのじゃ、おじさん。
Exit 8 is okay? Let me look at the mister, the mister.
おじさん？
Mister?
おじさんオッケー？普通の顔。
Is the mister okay? He has a normal face.
後ろ姿も普通。
His back looks normal too.
えーっと、エイト歯科医院オッケー？木・日休み。
Let's see, Eight Dental Clinic is okay? Closed on Thursday and Sunday.
アルバイトオッケー？
Part-time job poster, okay?
8番出口、分電盤室。
Exit 8, distribution board room.
ドッグサロンZUI、ZUI。
Dog Salon Zui, Zui.
司法書士、司法書士。
Judicial Scrivener, Judicial Scrivener.
えーっと、メイクアップアートオッケー？
Hmm, make-up art poster is okay?
ムーブフェスオッケー？
Move Fes poster is okay?
従業員専用、清掃...え、なくね？ないのじゃ。
Staff Only, Janitor Room... Eh, isn't something missing? There's nothing.
防犯カメラ作動中。防犯カメラもある。
Security camera in operation. The security camera is there too.
地下広場。え、異変ないのじゃ。
Underground plaza. Eh, there is no anomaly.
異変ねえのじゃ。なんなのじゃ。
No anomaly here either. What's going on?
このゲームのじゃ。
Is it this game...?
ない、ないよ、ないのじゃ。
Nothing, nothing's here, no anomaly.
進むのじゃ。
Let's move forward.
後ろ見る。ないのじゃ、ない！
Looking back. Nothing's there, nothing!
ふむふむふむ、進む、進む、進む。
Hmm, hmm, moving forward, moving, moving.
うわあ！見て！6、6、6！6なのじゃ！
Whoa! Look! 6, 6, 6! It's 6!
6なのじゃ！ねえ、異変なさすぎじゃない？
It's 6! Hey, isn't there too few anomalies?
全然異変ないのじゃ、なんで？わしがご利益担当じゃから？
No anomalies at all. Why? Is it because I bring good fortune?
わしがご利益担当じゃから。ご利益担当のわしのために、なくしてくれてるのじゃ？
Because I bring good luck. Are they removing them for the sake of lucky me?
だてじゃないのじゃ！
It's not just for show!
RTA勢として立候補させていただきますのじゃ。
I hereby announce my candidacy as a speedrunner.
よいしょ、進むのじゃ。
Heave-ho, moving forward.
え、早くね？
Wait, is he fast?
ここ、怖い怖い怖い怖い怖い怖い...早いのじゃ！
Here, scary, scary, scary... He's fast!
なんか早い！何？のっ...
He's somehow fast! What? Wh...
のじゃ！
Noja!
なんか、早くなかった？え？何？
Wait, wasn't he incredibly fast? Eh? What?
え、う、う、う、のじゃ。
Eh? Uh... Noja.
何？
What?
早かった。
He was fast.
なんか早かったのじゃ、何？
He was somehow super fast, what was that?
え、あ、あの、あの人さ、あのおじさんさ。
Uh, that, that person, that mister...
あのおじさんさ、早すぎてさ、多分さ、多分さ、わしがさ、のんびりさ...
That mister was so fast, probably, probably, if I had been taking my time...
のんびり行ってたらさ、のんびり行ってたら、多分捕まってたのじゃ。
If I were going slowly, if I were taking my time, I'd probably be caught.
のじゃ。
Yeah.
すす、進むのじゃ。7番ですし、進むのじゃ。
Let's m-move forward. It's number 7, let's move forward.
怖いのじゃ。怖いのじゃ。
Scary. It's scary.
あー。
Ah...
あ、ゆっくりのおじさんだ。ゆっくりのおじさんだ。
Oh, it's the slow-walking mister. The slow-walking mister.
おじさんのじゃ。
It's the man.
さっきの、ZUIよりずっと早いやつ、あんまり良くないネタだったっぽいのじゃ。
The one way before ZUI earlier... seemed to be a bad meme.
ちょっと、ちょっと切ないネタだったっぽいのじゃ。
It seems it was a slightly sad meme.
ちゃんと調べましたのじゃ、元ネタ。
I properly looked up the source material.
おじさん、普通のおじさん？
The man... just a normal man?
背中も普通？
His back is also normal?
背中も普通のおじさん。
The man has a normal back too.
背中の普通のおじさん。
A normal back, normal man.
エイト歯科、OK？
Eight Dental Clinic, OK?
アルバイト、パート、OK？
Part-time job poster, OK?
順番を頑張って覚えているのに、順番全部同じなのじゃ。
Even though I'm trying hard to memorize the order, they are all in the same order.
ZUI、OK？
ZUI poster, OK?
分電盤室、OK？
Distribution board room, OK?
司法書士、OK？
Judicial scrivener, OK?
メイクアップアート、OK？
Makeup art, OK?
MOVEFES、OK？
MOVEFES, OK?
防犯カメラ、OK？
Security camera, OK?
従業員用、従業員用。
Employees only, for employees.
地下広場。
Underpass.
え、異変ないのじゃ？
Eh, is there no anomaly?
防犯カメラもある。
There's a security camera too.
防犯カメラ、作動中。
"Security camera in operation" too.
異変ないのじゃ？
Is there no anomaly?
消火栓もあるのじゃ。
There's a fire hydrant too.
異変ないのじゃ。
There is no anomaly.
のじゃ。
Noja.
進むのじゃ。
Going forward.
え？
Huh?
ゼロ...
Zero...
なんでゼロ...
Why is it Exit 0...
のじゃ？
Noja?
なんでゼロだったの？
Why was it Exit 0?
なんでゼロだったの！？
Why was it Exit 0?!
何が、何が変だったのじゃ！？
What, what was wrong?!
え、なかった、異変ない。異変ないのじゃ！
Eh, there wasn't, no anomaly. There was no anomaly!
異変がないですし、のじゃ。
There was no anomaly, and...
え、異変ないのに...
Eh, even though there was no anomaly...
のじゃ？
Noja?
もう一回しっかり見てみますのじゃ。
I'll take another close look.
でも、やることは分かったのじゃ。
But I understand what to do now.
やることは分かったのじゃ。
I understand what to do now.
戻ってみれるの？
Can I go back?
戻ってみれるらしい。
Apparently I can try going back.
戻ってみるのじゃ。
I'll go back.
ダッシュできない。
I can't dash.
あれ？ダッシュできない異変ですのじゃ。
Ah? Is the inability to dash an anomaly?
のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ。
Noja, noja, noja, noja.
のじゃ。
Noja.
あ、戻れないっぽい。
Ah, it seems I can't go back.
もっかい頑張りますのじゃ。
I'll try hard again.
エイト歯科医院！
Eight Dental Clinic!
アルバイト募集！
Part-time job recruitment!
分電盤室！
Distribution board room!
オープン、ドッグオープン？
Open, Dog Open?
おじさんOK？おじさん大丈夫？
Uncle is OK? Is the uncle okay?
うん、大丈夫。
Yeah, he's okay.
司法書士OK？
Judicial scrivener OK?
メイクアップアートOK？
Makeup art OK?
MOVEFES OK？防犯カメラ？
MOVEFES OK? Security camera?
防犯カメラもありますのじゃ、地下広場。
There's a security camera too. Underpass.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
従業員専用、
Employees Only,
清掃員詰所。
Janitor's office.
よし。
Alright.
なに！なに！なに！何これ！
What! What! What! What is this!
やめて、のじゃ！
Stop it!
何！暗い、暗い、暗い！
What! It's dark, dark, dark!
う、行き止まり！？
Ah, a dead end?!
ちょ、ちょ、なんか音する、音する、音する！
Wait, wait, I hear something, I hear a sound!
う、何これ！？
Ugh, what is this?!
何！？
What?!
え？
Eh?
何！？
What?!
のじゃ？
Noja?
のじゃ、の、何で消えた？何...
Wh-Why did it disappear? What...
何？
What?
な...
Wh...
な、何で電気消えたのじゃ？
Wh-Why did the lights go out?
え？
Eh?
電気消えるの異変？
Is the lights turning off an anomaly?
ええ！？
Eeeh?!
え？
Eh?
い、今の、今のはそういう異変？今のはそういう異変なのじゃ？
W-Was that, was that an anomaly just now? Was that an anomaly?!
は、あーー！あーー！
Ah, aah! Aah!
いったん落ち着くのじゃ。
Let's calm down for a second.
びっくりしたのじゃ。
I was so scared.
いったん落ち着くのじゃ。
Let's calm down for a second.
いいったん落ち着くのじゃ。
何ぃ？
What is it?
いったん落ち着くのじゃ。
Let's calm down.
何なのエラー？
What was that error/glitch?
あー、びっくりしたのじゃ。
Ah, I was so scared.
なんか、のじゃ。
Like...
のじゃ。
Noja.
ちょ、ちょっとお水、お水を飲むのじゃ。
W-Wait, I'll drink some water.
お水も、お水も飲むのじゃ。
Water... I'll drink some water.
びっくりしたのじゃ。
I was so scared.
のじゃ。
Noja.
びっくりしたのじゃ。
I was so scared.
のじゃーー、
Nojaaa...
のじゃ。
Noja.
うん。
Yeah.
異変でしたのじゃ。
It was indeed an anomaly.
怖いのじゃ。
It's scary.
でも、でも頑張って引き返したのじゃ。
But, but I turned back as best as I could.
頑張って...
Doing my best...
あ、わしもびっくりしちゃったのじゃ。
Oh, I was so scared too.
わしちょっとホラゲ派遣無理かもなのじゃ。ホラゲ系VTuber...
I might not be cut out for horror games. A horror VTuber...
ホロライブホラゲ担当を目指していたんじゃが
I was aiming to be the horror game specialist in Hololive, but...
ホロライブホラゲ部門、1、VTuberを目指していたんじゃが
I was aiming to be the number one horror VTuber in Hololive, but...
ちょっとわしには、わしには無理そうですのじゃ。
I think it might be... it might be impossible for me.
今迄、今迄ありがとうのじゃ。ちょっと
Thank you for everything up until now. Just...
ちょっとびっくり系は、びっくり系は難しいですのじゃ。ちょっと
Jump-scare types are... they're really difficult for me. Just...
ちょっと中々
This is really...
中々大変ですのじゃ。
It's really tough, you know.
呼吸の、呼吸の吸いすぎで
Because of my breathing... breathing too fast...
呼吸の吸いすぎで体が痺れておりますのじゃ。
My body is getting numb from hyperventilating.
ちょっと、ちょっとソフィア心拍数計貸して欲しいのじゃ。
I wish... I wish Sophia would lend me a heart rate monitor.
今やばいのじゃ、100、100、100、200になるのじゃ。無理なのじゃ。頑張るのじゃ。
It's crazy right now. It's going to hit 100, 200... I can't do this. I'll do my best.
ちょっと一、一旦落ち着かせていただいてよろしいですのじゃ？
Could you... could you please let me calm down for a second?
ちょっと一旦、一旦ね
Just for a second, just a second...
うう、怖かった！怖かったのじゃ。
Ooh, that was scary! It was so scary.
ふう、きょ、びっくり系はするなのじゃ。びっくり系はするなのじゃ。
Phew, don't do jump-scares. Don't do jump-scares.
ううええ
Uuugh...
もう驚かさないで欲しいのじゃ。
I don't want to be scared anymore.
よし！行くのじゃ！
Alright! Let's go!
うう、全部、全部倒す、全部倒す、全部倒す！全部倒すのじゃー！
Ooh, I'll defeat them all, defeat them all! I'll defeat them all!
よし、よし、よし。えーっと、ノー、ノースモーキングオッケー？
Alright, alright. Let's see... No Smoking, okay?
えーっと、看板6個ある、オッケー？えーっと、歯科医院オッケー？
There are 6 posters, okay? The dental clinic poster is okay.
おじさんも見るのじゃ。アルバイト・パート大募集オッケー？
Let's check the middle-aged man too. Part-time job recruitment, okay?
おじさんの顔、オッケーなのじゃ。
The man's face is okay.
背中もオッケーなのじゃ。
His back is also okay.
分電盤室オッケー？
Distribution board room, okay?
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener, okay?
えーっと、メイクアップアートオッケー？ムーブフェスオッケー？防犯カメラはオッケー。
Makeup art, okay? Move Fes, okay? Security camera is okay.
防犯カメラもあるのじゃ。そして
There is a security camera. And...
従業員専用。何一つおかしくないのじゃ。
Staff Only. Nothing is out of the ordinary.
清掃員詰所もおかしくないのじゃ。
The janitor's room is also normal.
地下広場。うむ。
Concourse. Yep.
床にも天井にも異変はないんじゃなかろうか。
There shouldn't be any anomalies on the floor or ceiling, right?
あー、やっぱびっくりさせる系って良くないのじゃ。心臓に悪いですのじゃ。
Ah, jump-scare games are really bad. It's bad for the heart.
うう、怖かった。怖かった。
Ooh, that was scary. So scary.
え、ゼロ？
Huh, zero?
ゼロなのじゃ。何で？見たい。見たい。
It's zero. Why? I want to see. I want to see.
何で？今、何が異変だったの？今何が異変じゃったの？
Why? What was the anomaly just now? What was abnormal?
ないよ。異変ないのじゃ。
There wasn't any. There was no anomaly.
見直せ。
Look closely.
天井？どこ？
The ceiling? Where?
うわああ！
Aaaaah!
シミ？何？これ？何？何これ？
A stain? What? This? What? What is this?
何？もう
What? Seriously...
し、し、し、しみ？ええ
A... s... s... stain? Huh...
怖い。怖い。
It's scary. It's scary.
またゼロからなのじゃ。またゼロからなのじゃ。
It's back to zero. It's back to zero again.
よし！ゼロから頑張るのじゃ！
Alright! I'll do my best from zero!
わし、プレイ中はね、コメント欄見てないから。プレイ中はコメント欄見てないから大丈夫なのじゃ。
I don't look at the chat while playing, so it's fine.
振り返りの時だけ見てるのじゃ。よいしょ。
I only look during the reviews. Alright.
行くのじゃ。
Let's go.
ええ、なんかさ、地味な異変ちょっとずるいのじゃ。地味だから気付きづらいのじゃ。
Ugh, subtle anomalies are kind of cheating. They're hard to notice because they're subtle.
禁煙オッケー？ノースモーキングオッケー？
No Smoking, okay? No Smoking, okay?
えーっと、歯科医院オッケー？
Let's see, dental clinic, okay?
えーっと、パートオッケー？おじさんの顔も見ますのじゃ。おじさんの顔も普通なのじゃ。
Part-time job, okay? Let's check the man's face too. His face is normal.
普通、スマホ持ってる。背中もオッケーですのじゃ。うむ。
Normal, he has his smartphone. His back is also okay. Yes.
分電盤室オッケー。
Distribution board room, okay.
えーっと、オープンオッケー。司法書士オッケー。
Let's see, Open, okay. Judicial scrivener, okay.
メイクアップオッケー。ムーブフェスオッケー。防犯カメラオッケー。
Makeup, okay. Move Fes, okay. Security camera, okay.
分電盤室。
Distribution board room.
従業員専用。
Staff Only.
従業員専用。清掃員詰所。
Staff Only. Janitor's room.
防犯カメラ。
Security camera.
よし、行くのじゃー。
Alright, let's go.
あれ？
Huh?
え、このゲーム難しくない？
Wait, isn't this game really hard?
何が違ったんじゃ？何が違ったんじゃ？
What was different? What was different?
ちょ振り返り、振り返り、振り返り。教えて、教えて。
Wait, turn back, turn back, turn back. Tell me, tell me!
振り返りターンなのじゃ。何が違った？何が違った？
Is it the turn back turn? What was different? What was different?
おじさんがずっと見てた？
Was the middle-aged man staring at me the whole time?
なるほど、そういう異変もあるのじゃ。ちょっとパターンゲーなのじゃ、パターンゲー。
I see, so there are anomalies like that too. It's kind of a pattern-learning game, a pattern-learning game.
パターンゲー、パターンゲーなのじゃ！
A pattern-learning game! It's a pattern-learning game!
了解なのじゃ。う〜〜〜ん。
Got it. Hmmm...
行くのじゃ。え、もしかして最初めっちゃ運良かった？
Let's go. Wait, by any chance, was I super lucky at the start?
もしかして、めちゃ最初運良かったのじゃ？
Was I super lucky at the very beginning?
よし、行かせていただきますのじゃ！
Alright, I shall go now!
よいしょ、よいしょ。おじさんが見てるか、じゃ、見てるか判断するために
Yoisho, yoisho. To determine if the middle-aged man is looking or not,
おじさんからちょっと遠くにいなきゃいけないってことじゃろう？な？
I need to stay a little far away from him, right? Right?
禁煙、No Smoking、オッケー。
No Smoking, okay.
エイト歯科、オッケー。
Eight Dental Clinic, okay.
アルバイト、オッケー。おじさん見る？
Part-time job, okay. Let's look at the middle-aged man.
おぬしを見ておる。
He is looking at me.
おぬしを、見ておる。うむ、異変なし！
He is looking at me. Yep, no anomaly!
異変なし。分電盤室オッケー？
No anomaly. Electrical switchboard room, okay?
うむ。アルバイトパート大募集オッケー。
Yep. Part-time job recruitment, okay.
ドッグサロン、オッケー。司法書士、
Dog salon, okay. Judicial Scrivener,
司法書士オッケー。
Judicial Scrivener, okay.
うむ。メイクアップアート、オッケー。
Yep. Makeup art, okay.
メイクアップアート、オッケー。ムーブフェス、オッケー。
Makeup art, okay. Move Fes, okay.
防犯カメラもオッケー。
Security camera is also okay.
して、従業員専用。
And, Staff Only.
清掃員詰所。
Janitor Room.
消火栓。
Fire hydrant.
うむ。地下広場。
Yep. Underground Plaza.
異変なし、異変なーし！
No anomaly, no anomal-y!
これで合ってたら切れるのじゃ。これで合ってたらキレるのじゃ。キレてみせるのじゃ！
If this is correct, I'll be so mad. If this is correct, I'll lose it. I'll show you my rage!
ふーー！やっと1！やっと進めたのじゃ！
Phew! Finally Exit 1! I finally advanced!
ちょっとこのまま御利益パワーで、御利益パワーで行きたいのじゃ。1。よし、行きますのじゃ。
I want to keep going like this with divine blessing power, with divine blessing power. 1. Alright, let's go.
分かってきたのじゃ。ゲーム理解、丸。
I'm starting to get it. Game comprehension: Check.
ゲーム理解、二重丸。
Game comprehension: Double check.
はい、出口8、オッケー。禁煙、オッケー。
Yes, Exit 8, okay. No smoking, okay.
禁煙オッケー。
No smoking, okay.
6個看板ある。6個看板ある。
There are 6 signs. There are 6 signs.
8月8日エイト歯科。
August 8th, Eight Dental Clinic.
えっと、アルバイトパート。
Let's see, part-time job.
おじさん、普通の顔。わしのことも見ていない。
The middle-aged man has a normal face. He isn't looking at me either.
後ろ姿オッケー。
Back view, okay.
分電盤室オッケー。
Electrical switchboard room, okay.
ズイ、司法書士。
Zui, Judicial Scrivener.
メイクアップアート。
Makeup Art.
ムーブフェス。
Move Fes.
防犯カメラ。従業員専用、清掃員詰所。
Security camera. Staff Only, Janitor Room.
地下広場。
Underground Plaza.
ふむふむふむ。消火栓オッケー？
Hmm, hmm, hmm. Fire hydrant, okay?
後ろ見る。
Looking behind.
天井、床見る。
Looking at the ceiling and floor.
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
オッケーなのじゃ。進む！
It's okay. Moving forward!
進む！
Moving forward!
2！2！2！2！
2! 2! 2! 2!
2なのじゃ。もう勝ったのじゃ。
It's Exit 2. I've already won.
一回掴んでしまえば、一回掴んでしまえばもう勝ったも同然。
Once you get the hang of it, once you get the hang of it, you've basically won.
出口2行きますのじゃ！
Going to Exit 2!
ふむふむふむ。ちら。出口8、1、2、3、4、5、6ある。1、2、3、扉ある。
Hmm, hmm, hmm. Peek. Exit 8, there are 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 signs. There are 1, 2, 3 doors.
えー、禁煙オッケー。
Uh, No smoking, okay.
禁煙、No Smokingオッケーのじゃ。
No smoking, No Smoking is okay.
そう、勝つのじゃ。がははは。
Yes, I will win. Gahahaha.
軽いものじゃて。
It's an easy task.
おじさんちゃんと見るよ。おじさん？おじさんオッケー？
Let's look closely at the middle-aged man. Uncle? Uncle, okay?
おじさんの後ろ姿も見るよ。
I'll look at the middle-aged man's back view too.
おじさん後ろ姿オッケーなのじゃ！オッケーなのじゃ。よし、よし、よし、よし。
Uncle's back view is okay! It's okay. Good, good, good, good.
んで、エイト歯科オッケー。
And, Eight Dental Clinic, okay.
パートオッケー。
Part-time job, okay.
ズイ、オッケー。分電盤室オッケー。
Zui, okay. Electrical switchboard room, okay.
司法書士オッケー。
Judicial Scrivener, okay.
メイクアップアートオッケー。
Makeup Art, okay.
ムーブフェスオッケーなのじゃ。
Move Fes is okay.
んで、えっと、防犯カメラもオッケーなのじゃ。従業員専用、清掃員...
And, let's see, the security camera is also okay. Staff Only, Janitor...
地下広場、え、なくない？ないのじゃ、ないのじゃ。
Underground Plaza, wait, is it not there? It's not there! It's not there!
消火栓、うむ。
Fire hydrant, yep.
後ろから見るのじゃ。あ、もう1回天井とかね。
Let's look from behind. Ah, once more at the ceiling and stuff.
でも天井も見たのじゃ。
But I looked at the ceiling too.
天井も見たのじゃ。ふむふむふむ。
I looked at the ceiling too. Hmm, hmm, hmm.
よし、行くのじゃ。
Alright, let's go.
大丈夫なのじゃ。
It's fine.
答え合わせ、のじゃ！え？
Time for the result! Huh?
え、0？
Wait, 0?
0！？なんで、なんで、なんで！？なんで？
0?! Why, why, why?! Why?!
なんでじゃ？ちょっとのじゃ。
Why? Wait a minute.
ん？
Huh?
何が違ったのじゃ？点字ブロックが、お！
What was different? The tactile paving, oh!
本当だ！点字ブロックがツルツル！え、そんなのあり？そんなのなしなのじゃ！
It's true! The tactile paving is smooth! Wait, is that even allowed? That's not fair!
え、そんなのあるのじゃ？
Wait, is that a thing?
うわ、細かい。とても細かな... とても細かなのじゃ。
Wow, so detailed. It's so detailed...
意味ねえのじゃ。点字ブロックつるつる... あ！
It doesn't make any sense. The tactile paving is smooth... Ah!
こういうのもあるのじゃ。
There are things like this too.
なるほど。
I see.
あ、本当だ。こっからつるつるじゃなくなっている。
Ah, it's true. It's not smooth anymore from here.
ええ、なかなか面白いことを考えるのじゃ。
Wow, they think of some pretty interesting things.
見るとこいっぱいなのじゃ。
There are so many places to look.
ちょっと自分がゲーム制作者だったらどこにどういう異変を作りたいか考えながらやるのじゃ。
Let's play while thinking about where and what kind of anomalies I would make if I were a game developer.
難しいのじゃ。これ出れるかな、もし。
It's difficult. I wonder if I can escape.
もし出れるかのう？行けるか？
I wonder if I can exit? Can I make it?
うーんと...
Hmm...
行きますのじゃ、8。
Let's go, Exit 8.
つるつるじゃない。禁煙、No Smoking？
It's not smooth. "No Smoking"?
エイト歯科？エイト歯科？
Eight Dental Clinic? Eight Dental Clinic?
アルバイト大募集？
Now hiring part-time employees?
ちょっと人間の顔をじっくり見させていただきますのじゃ。
Let me take a closer look at that person's face.
わしを見ている？わしを見ていない！
Is he looking at me? He's not looking at me!
そして背中も大丈夫。カバンも持っているのじゃ。よし、よし、よし、よし。出口8。
And his back is fine. He is holding a bag. Okay, okay, okay. Exit 8.
アルバイトオッケー。
Part-time job poster, okay.
分電盤室オッケー。分電盤室オッケー。
Distribution board room, okay. Distribution board room, okay.
エイト？
Eight?
うわあ！何これ！
Whoa! What is this?!
これ異変ですのじゃ！これ異変！
This is an anomaly! This is an anomaly!
わし異変見つけた！わし異変見つけた！
I found an anomaly! I found an anomaly!
ねえ怖い顔あった！怖い顔あった！
Hey, there was a scary face! There was a scary face!
怖い顔あった！
There was a scary face!
のじゃ...
Oh dear...
びっくりした。びっくりした。1。
That scared me. That scared me. Exit 1.
恐ろしいですのじゃ。
That's terrifying.
はぁ... そっか、こういうのも、こういうのも見なきゃいけない。
Ah... I see, I have to look out for things like this too.
No Smokingオッケー。
No Smoking, okay.
ん？なんか階段...
Hmm? A staircase...
階段なのじゃ。明らかにおかしい。
It's a staircase. That's clearly strange.
階段。階段なのじゃ。
Stairs. It's stairs.
階段。上っちゃだめじゃろ。
Stairs. I shouldn't go up, right?
これ、え、ゴール？これゴール？これゴールなのじゃ？
Is this... wait, the goal? Is this the goal? Is this the goal?
え、でもまだ、まだ7回やってないよ。
Eh, but I haven't reached Exit 7 yet.
まだ7回やってないのじゃ。
I haven't gone through 7 times yet.
え、7回やってないから異変なのじゃ。
Since I haven't reached 7, this must be an anomaly.
ね、7、7回やって、異変なのじゃ！
Right, 7, 7 times, it's an anomaly!
だって、だって、7、7と8、7と8、7と8じゃろ？
Because, because, 7 and 8, 7 and 8, it's supposed to be 7 then 8, right?
7と8じゃろ？7と8。
7 and 8, right? 7 and 8.
7と...
7 and...
え、出られる？本当？本当？どっち？
Wait, can I exit? Really? Really? Which is it?
ちょっと、ちょっとコメント見ちゃ...
Let me, let me check the comments...
の...
No...
のじゃ。
Noja.
いや。
No.
出るのじゃ！
I'm going out!
え、だってまだ、まだ1じゃしね。まだ1じゃしね。まだ1じゃしね。
Because it was still... it was still Exit 1. It was still Exit 1.
あ、0。あ、0。
Ah, 0. Ah, 0.
のじゃ？
Noja?
まだ1じゃしね。
It was still Exit 1, right?
何？暗い。暗い。暗い。ね、暗い。
What? It's dark. Dark. Dark. Hey, it's dark.
のじゃ？
Noja?
戻された。何もないかい。
I was sent back. Nothing was there?
え、でも、でも、まだまだ最初だったから。まだ1じゃったから。まだ1じゃったから、そんな、そんなのじゃ。
But it was still the beginning. It was still Exit 1. Since it was still Exit 1, it's fine.
ちょっとおじさんチェックするのじゃ。
Let's check the middle-aged man.
おじさん、失礼しますのじゃ。
Excuse me, mister.
傷の浅いうちにね。
While the damage is minimal.
はい、8月8日オープンのじゃ。
Yes, grand opening on August 8th.
アルバイト募集のじゃ。
Part-time job recruitment.
オープン、NEW、ZUIのじゃ。
Grand opening, New Zui, okay.
分電盤室のじゃ。
Distribution board room, okay.
ええと...
Uh...
司法書士トラブルのじゃ。
Judicial scrivener trouble poster, okay.
メイクアップ。
Makeup.
1、2、3、4、5、6。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
防犯カメラ。
Security camera.
地下広場。
Underground plaza.
従業員専用。清掃員...
Employees only. Cleaning staff...
消火栓、ない。
Fire hydrant, none.
異変ないのじゃ。
There are no anomalies.
うん、異変ないのじゃ。進む。
Yeah, no anomalies. Moving forward.
もう一回振り返る。異変なし。
Looking back once more. No anomalies.
進むのじゃ。
Let's move forward.
ふん、ふん、ふん、ふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
1。はい、戻ってきた！はい、戻ってきたのじゃ！
Exit 1. Yes, I'm back! Yes, I came back!
だからさっき階段の上上ったのはね、しょうがない、いいことなのじゃ。
So going up the stairs earlier was... well, it couldn't be helped, it was a good thing.
別に、ここで取り返せばいいから。ここで取り返せばいいから大丈夫ですのじゃ。
Anyway, I can just make up for it here. I can make up for it here, so it's fine.
よし、よし、よし。行くのじゃ！
Okay, okay, okay. Let's go!
8。
Exit 8.
禁煙、No Smokingオッケー。1、2、3、4、5、6。
No smoking, No Smoking okay. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
え、なんか出てる。
Eh, something is coming out.
なんか出てる。なんかドロドロ出てるのじゃ！
Something is coming out. Something slimy is coming out!
ね、右からドロドロ出てた。
There was a muddy liquid dripping from the right.
右からドロドロ出てた。
A muddy liquid was dripping from the right.
右からドロドロ出てたのじゃ。
It was dripping from the right.
２〜
Two...
２〜！
Two!
はい、２に来ましたね。のじゃ。
Alright, we've reached number two.
よしよしよし。得意になってきた。
Alright, alright, alright. I'm getting good at this.
このゲーム全部理解した。分かってきたのじゃ。
I understand everything about this game now. I've got it down.
行くのじゃ。
Let's keep going.
次は３。
Next is three.
1、2、3、4、5、6、オッケー。出口8、オッケー。1、2、3、ドア...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay. Exit 8, okay. 1, 2, 3, doors...
ノー・スモーキングのじゃ。
And "No Smoking" is there.
床もツルツルじゃないし。
The floor isn't slippery either.
人間の顔を見るのじゃ。
I need to check the person's face.
待っててあげる。
I'll wait for you.
人間来るの待っててあげる。
I'll wait for the human to come.
わし優しいから。
Because I'm nice.
見られてない。
He's not looking at me.
He's not looking.
おじさんも大丈夫。
The uncle is fine too.
よしよしよし。エイト歯科医のじゃ。
Alright, alright, alright. Eight Dental Clinic is there.
アルバイト、オッケーですのじゃ。
Part-time job poster, okay.
分電盤室、オッケーですのじゃ。
Distribution Board Room, okay.
ZUIのじゃ。
Zui's poster is there.
司法書士のじゃ。
Judicial Scrivener poster.
メイクアップ、アートのじゃ。
Makeup art poster.
天井とかも何も無いのじゃ。コンコース、オッケー。
Nothing on the ceiling either. Concourse is okay.
従業員専用、ムーブフェス。
Staff Only, Move Fes.
防犯カメラ...
Security camera...
きゃー！ごめっ！ごめっ！固まっちゃった！ごめっ、びっくりして！
Scream! Sorry, sorry! I froze! Sorry, it startled me!
何何何何！何？！音する！音する！音する！助けて！助けて！
What, what, what, what?! What?! I hear a noise! Noise! Noise! Help! Help!
何何何何！なんなのじゃ！なんなのじゃ！絶対変なのじゃ！
What is it?! What's going on?! Something is definitely wrong!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
なんか、なんか、音。なんか音。何かの音。何の音かも分からなかった。
There was a noise, some kind of noise. Some sound. I couldn't even tell what kind of sound it was.
のじゃ...のじゃ...
Oh my god...
な、な、何の音か分からなかった。
I... I couldn't tell what sound it was.
何の音か分からなかったけど、なんか来た。
I don't know what that sound was, but something came.
うぅ...ふぅ...えぇ...
Ugh... phew... ah...
逃げられた？逃げられた？怖いのじゃ、何なのじゃ！
Did I escape? Did I escape? That was scary, what was that?!
びっくりした。え、何が、何があったかも分からない。
I was so startled. I don't even know what happened.
何が、何が行ってたのかも分からない。
I don't even know what was going on.
びっくりした、びっくりした、びっくりしたのじゃ、びっくりした、びっくりしたのじゃ。
That startled me, that startled me, it really startled me.
なんか、なんか、なんか、のじゃ。
That was... something else...
え、違うの。一時停止、一時停止。一時停止、一時停止押したつもりもなく、
Wait, no. Pause, pause. I didn't even mean to press pause,
なんか、びっくりして、
but I was so startled,
びっくりしてキーボードをバーンって押したら、
that when I slammed the keyboard,
キーボード、キーボードをバーンって押したら、なんか画面止まったのじゃ。
when I slammed the keyboard, the screen suddenly paused.
画面止まったのじゃ。
The screen paused.
びっくりしたのじゃ。
It startled me so much.
ふぅ、水飲もう、水飲もう。一旦、一旦水、のじゃ。
Phew, let's drink water, let's drink water. First, let's get some water.
ね、どうしよう。これでさ、これでわしがさ、本当は可愛くないのじゃ、お主らにバレちゃったらどうしよう。
Oh no, what should I do? What if... what if you all find out I'm actually not cute?
ね、わしがさ、
I mean, if I...
わし、わし、あぁ、噛んじゃった。わしの叫び声をさ、聞いてさ、
I... Ah, I stuttered. If you hear my screams...
わしの叫び声を聞いてさ、お主らがさ、お主らがさ、あぁ、
If you hear my screams, and you all... and you all...
なんか、メラの叫び声可愛くなくて異変とか思ったらどうしよう。どうしよう、のじゃ。
what if you think, "Mera's scream isn't cute, that's an anomaly"? What should I do?
のじゃ〜
Oh dear...
頑張って、２次元、2.5次元？に喜んでもらいたくて、頑張って可愛いやってるのに、
I try so hard to sound cute to make you all happy,
叫んでるとこで可愛くないって思われたらどうしよう。
but what if you think I'm not cute when I scream?
のじゃ〜
Oh my...
『その時は引き返してみる？』進んでほしいのじゃ！引き返さないでほしいのじゃ！
"Should we turn back then?" I want to move forward! I don't want to turn back!
わしの声が可愛くないって思っても引き返さないでほしいのじゃ！
Even if you think my voice isn't cute, please don't turn back!
共に諦めて、諦めて共に一緒に歩んでほしいのじゃ。諦めてほしいのじゃ。
Just accept it and walk with me. Please accept it.
よし、３行くのじゃ。
Alright, let's go to three.
ふぅ、３行くのじゃ。よし。
Phew, let's go to three. Alright.
よし。ちら。はぁ。
Alright. Glancing. Phew.
1、2、3、4、5、6。出口８、ツルツルじゃない。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. Exit 8, the floor isn't slippery.
えーと、禁煙オッケーのじゃ。
Let's see, "No Smoking" is okay.
えーと、おじさんをゆっくり見よう。
Let's see, let's watch the uncle carefully.
エイト歯科医オッケーのじゃ。よいしょ。
Eight Dental Clinic, okay.
おじさん、おじさん、
Uncle, uncle...
オッケー。おじさんオッケー？おじさんオッケーそう。
Okay. Uncle, are you okay? The uncle seems okay.
おじさんオッケーそうなのじゃ。歯科医アルバイト募集、
The uncle seems okay. Dental Clinic part-time job poster,
分電盤室、
Distribution Board Room,
オープン、ドッグサロンZUI、
New Open, Dog Salon Zui,
司法書士、
Judicial Scrivener,
司法書士オッケー。メイクアップオッケー。
Judicial Scrivener okay. Makeup okay.
えーと、ムーブフェスオッケー。
Let's see, Move Fes okay.
防犯カメラオッケー。天井も見るのじゃ。地下広場。
Security camera okay. Checking the ceiling too. Underground Plaza.
うん、うん、うん。異変なし。
Yep, yep, yep. No anomalies.
分電盤室、従業員専用、
Distribution Board Room, Staff Only,
清掃員詰所、えーと、消火栓、
Janitor Office, let's see, fire hydrant,
うん。異変見えない。よしよしよし。大丈夫？
Yeah, I don't see any anomalies. Alright. Is it okay?
後ろ向いても、下向いても大丈夫。大丈夫のじゃ。
It's fine even if I look back or look down. It's okay.
うん、うん、大丈夫。
Yep, yep, it's fine.
いくのじゃ
I'll go...
よし
Alright.
次は行けるんじゃ
I think I can make it this time...
４！
Four!
４なのじゃー
It's four!
怖い
I'm scared.
びっくりさせないでほしいのじゃ
I wish it wouldn't scare me.
よしよしよしよしよし
Good, good, good, good, good...
折り返し
The turnaround...
半分なのじゃ
We're halfway there!
行くのじゃ
Let's go.
よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho...
んっと
Let's see...
チラ
*Peek*
うわ、二人いるのじゃ！
Whoa, there are two of them!
何？！
What?!
二人いた！
There were two of them!
二人いたのじゃ
ダブル
Double...
ダブルサイクロンジョーカーなのじゃー
Double CycloneJoker!
うう、怖い
Ugh, scary...
え、なんか、これさ
Um, so about this...
二人いると思ってすぐ逃げなかったら
If I see two people and don't run away immediately...
絶対に二人がかりでわしのこと
they would absolutely double-team me...
二人がかりでわしのこと
both of them would...
わしのこと、捕まえようとしてるんじゃろ？
They're trying to catch me, aren't they?
うう、びっくり
Ugh, what a shock...
びっくりしたのじゃ
That really scared me!
うん
Yeah.
でも５、でも５
But it's 5, it's 5...
でも５なのじゃ、分かりやすい
But it's 5! That's easy to understand.
分かりやすい変はありがたいのじゃ
I appreciate easy-to-understand anomalies.
すぐ逃げることができるからな
Since I can run away immediately.
よしよしよしよしよし
Good, good, good, good, good...
行くのじゃ
Let's go.
のじゃ
...ja.
待って、重い
Wait, it's laggy.
重い、重い
Laggy, laggy...
チラ
*Peek*
１、２、３、４、５、６、オッケー
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
お部屋も３つあるのじゃ
There are three rooms too.
禁煙もある？
Is the "No Smoking" sign there?
うん
Yes.
禁煙もある？
Is the "No Smoking" sign there?
おじさんの顔見させていただきますのじゃ
Let me check the middle-aged man's face.
おじさんの顔？
The mister's face?
お顔見せて
Show me your face.
お顔大丈夫のじゃ？
Is your face okay?
お背中も大丈夫ですのじゃ
Your back is fine too.
よしよしよしよし
Good, good, good, good.
それでは
And now...
床もつるつるじゃないですのじゃ
The floor isn't slippery either.
はい、歯科医院オッケー
Yes, dental clinic poster is okay.
歯科医院オッケー
Dental clinic poster is okay.
アルバイトオッケー
Part-time job poster is okay.
うん
Yes.
ドッグ？
Dog?
ドッグオッケー？ 犬オッケー？
Dog is okay? Dog is okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Breaker room is okay?
ええと
Let's see...
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener poster is okay?
ええと
Let's see...
メイクアップオッケー？
Makeup poster is okay?
MOVE FESオッケー？
MOVE FES poster is okay?
防犯カメラもオッケーですのじゃ
Security camera is also okay.
地下広場？
Concourse?
天井もオッケーそう
The ceiling seems okay too.
床もオッケーそう
The floor seems okay too.
消火栓オッケー？
Fire hydrant is okay?
うん、うん、うん、うん
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
防犯カメラもある
There's a security camera too.
よし
Alright.
行くのじゃ
Let's go.
のじゃ
...ja.
ううううー
Uuuuu...
６！シックスなのじゃー！
6! It's six!
あと２個、あと２個！
Two more, two more!
あと２個、あと２個
Two more, two more...
のじゃ
...ja.
いやあ、長かったのじゃ
Man, that was a long way.
ちょ、ここで
Wait, right here...
ここで絶対に決めるのじゃ
I'm absolutely ending it here.
ここで絶対に決めますのじゃ
I will definitely finish it here.
ここで
Right here.
よし、行くのじゃ
Alright, let's go.
覚えた、完全に、全てを
I've memorized it. Completely. Everything.
はい、おじさんオッケー、おじさんいるのじゃ
Yes, mister is okay, mister is here.
つるつるじゃない、床オッケー
Not slippery, floor is okay.
天井オッケー
Ceiling is okay.
ん？
Hmm?
禁煙オッケー
No Smoking sign is okay.
おじさん見ますのじゃ
Watching the mister...
１、２、３、４、５、６、オッケー
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
おじさん見せて
Mister, let me see.
わしのこと見てない
He's not looking at me.
わしに興味ないおじさん、オッケー
He has no interest in me, okay.
オッケー
Okay.
エイト歯科医院オッケー
Eight Dental Clinic is okay.
アルバイトオッケー
Part-time job is okay.
ドッグサロンオッケー？
Dog salon is okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Breaker room is okay?
うん、うん、うん
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
上を見る？地下広場？
Looking up? Concourse?
もっと上を見る
Looking further up.
天井、顔ない
Ceiling, no faces.
司法書士オッケー
Judicial scrivener is okay.
メイクアップオッケー
Makeup is okay.
MOVE FESオッケー
MOVE FES is okay.
従業員オッケー
Staff only door is okay.
防犯カメラオッケー
Security camera is okay.
うむ
Hmm.
いいんじゃなかろうか
I think it should be fine.
よし、消火栓もある
Alright, fire hydrant is there too.
消火栓もある
Fire hydrant is there too.
改めて振り返ると
Looking back again...
うん、大丈夫。進むのじゃ
Yeah, it's fine. Let's move forward.
うん
Yep.
のじゃ！な、な、セブン！セブン！セブンのじゃー！
It is! Se... Se... Seven! Seven! It's seven!
いやあ、早いもので
Wow, how time flies...
早いもので１時間、皆様にお付き合いいただき
We've been going for an hour now. Thank you all for joining me...
ましたけどね
I did, but...
わしの旅もそろそろ終わりそうにのじゃ
It seems my journey is also about to end.
もう流スタにみおとさないのじゃ 覚えたのじゃ
I definitely won't miss anything now. I've memorized it.
こんだけやれば覚えるのじゃ
If I do it this much, I'll remember it.
いくら記憶力のないタイプのサラマンダーだとは言えど
No matter how forgetful of a salamander I may be...
行けますのじゃ
...I can do this!
よし
Alright.
しっしょ
しっしょ しっしょ しっしょ
Let's go, let's go, let's go...
床オッケー？
Floor okay?
床オッケー 床オッケー
Floor okay, floor okay.
ノースモーキングオッケー
No smoking sign okay.
ノースモーキングオッケー？
No smoking sign okay?
おじさんの顔見せていただきますのじゃ
Let me see your face, mister.
見せて！
Show me!
見せてのじゃ
Show me.
お顔オッケー！
Face is okay!
お顔大丈夫
His face is normal.
お背中も大丈夫、スマホも持ってる
His back is normal too, and he has his phone.
よし
Okay.
行くのじゃ
Moving on.
エイト歯科医院
Eight Dental Clinic...
何度も見た
...I've seen it many times.
けのじゃ
But...
アルバイトパート大募集
Part-time job recruitment...
何度も見た
...I've seen this many times too.
時給が千円
The hourly wage is 1,000 yen.
あ
Ah.
お顔ある！ねえお主らお顔ある！
There are faces! Hey guys, there are faces on the ceiling!
わしもやったこれ お顔ある！！
I fell for this before! There are faces on the ceiling!!
お顔あるお顔ある！
There are faces! There are faces!
はーち！！
Eight!!
はち はち！
Eight! Eight!
エイト！
Eight!
はぁ 早いもので
Sigh... That was quick.
八番出口ですか
Exit 8, is it?
八番に来ましたのじゃ
We've reached Exit 8.
それでは 進ませていただきますのじゃ
Well then, allow me to proceed.
進ませていただきますのじゃ
Allow me to proceed.
覚えゲーですのじゃ
It's a memory game.
ここで異変がなければ
If there's no anomaly here...
ノースモーキングオッケー？
No smoking sign okay?
床ツルツルじゃないオッケー？
Floor isn't shiny, okay?
おじさんの顔見る
Checking the mister's face.
おじさんの顔大丈夫そう
His face seems okay.
わしのこと見てない スマホ持ってる 背中もオッケー
He's not looking at me. He has his phone. His back is okay.
よしよしよしよし
Good, good, good, good.
8月8日オッケー
August 8th is okay.
アルバイトパート大募集オッケー
Part-time job poster is okay.
そして
And...
ニューオープンオッケー？ ニューオープンオッケー？
New Open poster okay? New Open okay?
分電盤室オッケー？
Breaker room okay?
最後だからちゃんと見よう
Let's check carefully since this is the end.
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial Scrivener poster okay?
うん
Yep.
メイクアップオッケー？
Makeup Art poster okay?
ムーブフェスオッケー
Move Fes poster okay.
防犯カメラオッケー
Security camera poster okay.
最後だからもう一回ちゃんと見るのじゃ 消火栓
It's the end, so let me check carefully once more. Fire hydrant...
清掃員詰所 3部屋だよね？ 3部屋だよね？
Janitor's Office. There are three rooms, right? Three rooms?
従業員専用 2部屋目、上にもあるし
Staff Only is the second room, the vent is up there...
天井もないし
...no anomaly on the ceiling...
分電盤室あるし 地下広場だし
...there's the Breaker Room, and the Concourse sign is there...
エイト歯科だし
...the Dental Clinic is there...
木、木曜休みの エイト歯科だし
...the Dental Clinic is closed on Thursdays, okay...
えっと アルバイト
And the part-time job poster...
ん？
Huh?
なんかポスターデカくね？ そういうのは無し？
Aren't the posters kind of huge? Is that not a thing?
こんなデカかった？
Were they always this big?
こんなバランスだったっけ？ ん？
Was the balance like this? Huh?
こんなバランスだった？
Was this the ratio?
空白の使い方違くない？
Isn't the spacing different?
画面こんなんだったっけ？
Was the screen like this?
ドアと同じサイズじゃない？ 気のせいか
Aren't they the same height as the doors? Or am I imagining things?
でもこんなデカくなかった気がするのじゃ
But I really don't think they were this big.
なんか比率がおかしい 画面の比率がおかしいのじゃ
The aspect ratio is weird. The screen's aspect ratio is off!
こんな比率だったっけ？ これ異変じゃない？
Was the ratio like this? Isn't this an anomaly?
なんかこれ75%くらいな気がするのじゃ これのサイズ
I feel like they're usually only 75% of this size.
こんなデカくなく… ん？
They shouldn't be this bi— Huh?
戻る！ 戻る戻る戻る戻る戻る戻る戻る！
Go back! Go back, go back, go back, go back, go back!!
戻る！ 8！
Go back! Eight!
8！ 8のじゃ！ え？ ん？ 8ということは？ 何？ ん？
Eight! It says eight! Eh? Huh? What does eight mean? What?
ん？ これは間違いじゃないから8？ もう一回遊べるドン？
Huh? It's exit 8 because it wasn't an anomaly? We get to play again?
ほらね！こんなデカくなかった！ ほら！こんなデカくなかったのじゃ！
See?! They weren't this big! Look! They weren't this big before!
こんなデカくなかったのじゃ！
They were definitely not this big!
おじさん、ん？まだ続くの？おじさん見るのじゃ おじさん見てない スマホ持ってる 背中
Mister... Huh? It's still going? Checking the mister. He's not looking. He has his phone. Back...
オッケー　背中オッケー
Okay. My back is okay.
8　えーと
8, let's see...
募集...
Recruiting...
分電盤室
Distribution board room.
えー　ZUI
Uh, ZUI...
司法書士　6枚あるからオッケー
Judicial Scrivener. There are six, so okay.
何何何何何何何何！
What, what, what, what, what, what, what!
お、男怖い！男怖いよ！
T-The man is scary! The man is scary!
男怖い！男怖い！男怖い！やめて！やめて！やめて！
The man is scary! Stop! Stop! Stop!
何何何？何？何？何何？何？
What, what, what? What? What? What, what? What?
長い、長い、何何何？何何？
It's long, it's long! What, what, what? What, what?
ま、まだ続くの？何！？
I-Is it still going? What!?
え？え？何なのじゃ？
Huh? Uh, what is that?
うい、水来た　怖い
Oh, water came. Scary.
怖いのじゃ　水
It's scary. Water...
水来た　おじさん見る
Water came. I'll watch the mister.
おじさん見る　おじさん、わしのこと見てない　オッケー
I'll watch him. He's not looking at me. Okay.
背中も大丈夫？
Is my back okay too?
ああ、怖いのじゃ
Ah, it's scary.
やっぱり、ね、音、音、苦手　音、苦手　音、苦手
As I thought, sound... sound... I'm bad with sounds.
音びっくりするからやめてほしいのじゃ
I wish they'd stop because the sounds scare me.
はい　8月8日オッケー
Yes, August 8th is okay.
1、2、3、4、5、6オッケー　アルバイトオッケー
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay. Part-time job is okay.
分電盤室　出口8オッケー
Distribution board room. Exit 8 is okay.
えー、司法書士オッケー　天井も変なの無い？
Uh, judicial scrivener is okay. Nothing weird on the ceiling?
うー、まだバクバクしてる　メイクアップアーティストオッケー
Ooh, my heart is still pounding. Makeup artist is okay.
えーと、のじゃ
Let's see...
MOVEFESオッケー　MOVEFESオッケー
MOVEFES is okay. MOVEFES is okay.
え、MOVEFESオッケー　防犯カメラオッケー
Eh, MOVEFES is okay. Security camera is okay.
防犯カメラオッケー
Security camera is okay.
従業員専用
Employees only.
ああ、怖い、怖い、怖い、怖い
Ah, scary, scary, scary, scary.
待って何！？また変なの付いてる　真ん中に付いてる
Wait, what!? Something weird is on it again. In the middle.
異変なのじゃ　異変しかない　異変しかないのじゃ
It's an anomaly. Nothing but anomalies.
これ、これ何？これ、正解しないと帰れない感じなのじゃ？
What, what is this? Do I have to get it right to go home?
水、水飲んでいいのじゃ？
Water... can I drink water?
水飲むのじゃ　失礼しますのじゃ
I'll drink water. Excuse me.
疲れてないのじゃ
I'm not tired.
疲れてないけど、びっくりした
I'm not tired, but I was startled.
びっくりが体に残ってるのじゃ　びっくりが体に残ってるのじゃ
The startle is remaining in my body.
びっくりして、あの、あの、びっくりしたのが体に残ってるのじゃ
Startled, um, the startle is remaining in my body.
水飲むのじゃ
I'll drink water.
疲れてはいないのじゃ
I'm not tired.
よし　落ち着くのじゃ　行きますのじゃ
Alright. Calm down. Let's go.
そろそろ帰りたいのじゃ　え、でも結構もう見っけたんじゃない？異変
I want to go home soon. But haven't I found a lot of anomalies?
結構いっぱいの異変見た気がしますのじゃ
I feel like I've seen quite a lot of anomalies.
ちら、ちら
Peek, peek.
ツルツルじゃない　ツルツルじゃない
It's not slippery. It's not slippery.
ノースモーキング禁煙オッケー
No Smoking, smoke-free is okay.
ちょっとおじさんをね、待ちますのじゃ
I'm going to wait for the mister.
おじさん　1、2、3...
Mister, 1, 2, 3...
おじさん、失礼いたしますのじゃ
Mister, excuse me.
おじさんわしのこと見てない　わしにはあまり興味ない
He's not looking at me. He doesn't have much interest in me.
背中もオッケー　背中もオッケー
My back is okay too. My back is okay too.
えーと　8月8日オッケー
Let's see... August 8th is okay.
8月8日オッケー　パートオッケー
August 8th is okay. Part-time is okay.
1、2、3、4、5、6　分電盤室オッケー
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, distribution board room is okay.
ZUIオッケー　ZUIオッケー　ZUIオッケー
ZUI is okay. ZUI is okay. ZUI is okay.
えーと、疲れた　疲れたとか言っちゃった　びっくりしちゃった
Let's see, I'm tired. I said I'm tired. I got startled.
え、司法書士オッケー
Uh, judicial scrivener is okay.
えー、メイクアップオッケー
Uh, makeup is okay.
MOVEFESオッケー　防犯カメラオッケー
MOVEFES is okay. Security camera is okay.
従業員専用　えー、清掃員詰所
Employees only. Janitor's office.
えーと、消火栓
Let's see, fire hydrant.
地下広場　え、これ、これ行けるんじゃないのじゃ？
Underground plaza. Eh, can't I go this way?
これ、これ行けるんじゃない？行けるんじゃない？
Can't I go this way? Can't I?
ちょっとこれでいけなかったら泣いちゃうからちゃんと
If I can't go, I'll cry, so...
もう一回ちゃんと見直すのじゃ
I'll double-check properly again.
地下広場
Underground plaza.
うん、顔も変わってない　顔も変わってない
Yeah, the faces haven't changed either.
ドッグ　ノースモーキング貼ってある
Dog. No Smoking is posted.
1、2、3、ドア1、2、3個ある
1, 2, 3, there are 1, 2, 3 doors.
うん、1、2、6ある
Yeah, there are 1, 2, 6.
ドアノブ　ツルツルじゃない
Doorknob. It's not slippery.
えー、天井にも何も無い
Uh, nothing on the ceiling either.
え、これ来たのでは？
Eh, did it come?
一応、一応ね。
Just in case, just to be sure.
これ来たのでは？
Wait, is this it?
これ来たのじゃ！
This is it!
勝ったのじゃ！
I won!
それでは皆さん、今までありがとうございましたのじゃ。
Well then, everyone, thank you so much for everything.
出口！
The exit!
出口！出口！出口！
Exit! Exit! Exit!
本物の出口なのじゃ！
It's the real exit!
やったのじゃ！クリア！
I did it! Cleared!
出口８！
Exit 8!
ああ、明るい。太陽光浴びてなくて頭おかしくなってたのじゃ。
Ah, it's so bright. I was going crazy without any sunlight.
うわあーー！クリアーーー！
Wow! Cleared!
ぴよぴよ、ぴよぴよ。
Chirp chirp, chirp chirp.
ぴよぴよ、ぴよぴよ、ぴよぴよ。
Chirp chirp, chirp chirp, chirp chirp.
ぴよぴよ。
Chirp chirp.
やったのじゃーー！
I did it!
頑張ったのじゃ。
I worked hard.
これなかなか、なかなか頑張ったのじゃ。
This was quite, quite tough, but I did my best.
すごい怖かった。すごい怖かった。
It was so scary. So scary.
すごいびっくり多かった。
There were so many jump scares.
すごいびっくり多くなかった？
Weren't there so many jump scares?
うわあ、クリアしたのじゃーー！
Wow, I cleared it!
何？「異変コンプリートの旅」って？「異変コンプリートの旅」って何？
What is "Anomalies Completed Voyage"? What's that?
異変集めみたいなのができるの？
Can we collect anomalies now?
「見つかっていない異変が23個あります」
"There are 23 anomalies that have not been found."
のじゃ？のじゃ？のじゃ？
Noja? Noja? Noja?
ここからが本番？23個？まだあるの？
Is this where the real game begins? 23? There are more?
じゃあ、もう一周ぐらいはやるのじゃ。じゃあやる前に一旦、どうしようかな。
Then let's do one more run. But before that, what should I do?
やる前に一旦、今日出そうと思っていた告知を出していいのじゃ？
Before starting, can I post the announcement I planned to release today?
ちょっと一旦告知を出させてほしいのじゃ。一旦、遊ぶから。
Let me just post the announcement first, since we're going to play anyway.
遊ぶ前にちょっと、ちょっと待ってほしいのじゃ。
Before we play, please wait a little bit.
ちょっと一瞬Twitterでね。Twitterでの、あの、よいしょ。お面かぶって。
Just a moment on Twitter. On Twitter... let me put on the mask.
Twitterでの告知したいことがね、あったからね。ちょっとそれだけツイートさせてほしいのじゃ。
Since there was something I wanted to announce on Twitter. Let me just tweet that.
ツイートだけさせてほしいのじゃ。よいしょ。
Just let me tweet. There we go.
「遊び回りたい」歌枠リレーを日曜日にやるんじゃけど、
I'm doing a singing relay on Sunday...
それの告知をちょっとツイートだけさせてほしいのじゃ。したのじゃ。
I just wanted to tweet that announcement. I did it.
おぬしらしたから、おぬしらしたから、あの、リツイートとね、いいねしてきてほしいのじゃ。
Since I did it, you guys, please retweet and like it.
リツイートといいねしてきてほしいのじゃ。
Please retweet and like it.
ちょっとリツイートといいねしてきてほしいのじゃ。
で、わしその間にお手洗い行ってくるから。お手洗い行ってくるから、
And I'll go to the restroom in the meantime. I'll go to the restroom,
ちょっと待っててほしいのじゃ。
so please wait a bit.
お手洗い行ったら続きやるのじゃ。お持ちくださいですのじゃ。
Once I'm back, we'll continue. Please wait.
よいしょ。
There we go.
ただいまにゃのじゃ。よいしょ。
I'm back. There we go.
おぬしら、さっき出した告知、いいねとリツイートしてくれた？
Did you guys like and retweet the announcement I just made?
いいねとリツイートしたのじゃ？拡散...
Did you like and retweet it? Spread the word...
してくれたのじゃ？
Did you do that for me?
してくれた人ありがとうなのじゃ
Thank you to whoever did it.
よいしょ
There we go.
いつもでしたら わし あんま配信時間長いタイプじゃないんじゃが
Usually, I'm not the type to stream for very long...
配信時間が あんまり長いタイプじゃないんじゃが
I'm not really the type to stream for long hours, but...
ちょっといけそうな気がしてきた
I feel like I can pull it off now.
いけそうな気がしてきたから
Since I feel like I can do it,
やってみるのじゃ
I'm going to give it a try.
うん 今日はね あの いつもね遊びまわり隊が配信する時
Yeah, today, you see... usually when the Asobimawaritai streams,
だいたいね おおよそ美良が19時で 20時からソピアで
typically, Mira is around 19:00, Sopia starts at 20:00,
21時からつづりがやって 今日子が22時くらいとか
Tsudzuri does 21:00, and Kyoko is around 22:00.
まあなんかそういう日もあったりするんじゃが
Well, sometimes we have days scheduled like that,
そういう日もあったりするんじゃが
sometimes we have schedules like that, but...
今日はね ソピアがね 23時 なんかいつもと時間違うのとね
today, Sopia is streaming at 23:00. The time is different from usual,
つづりがね 今日お休みだからね
and Tsudzuri has the day off today.
やっちゃおうかなと思って
So I thought I'd just stream!
I thought I'd go ahead and stream.
うん
Yeah.
やから
So,
今日は
today,
やってみようかな 今日金曜日 確かに今日金曜日じゃし
I'll give it a go. Today is Friday, and since it is Friday,
やっていこうかなと
I think I'll play.
思いますのじゃ
That's what I'm thinking.
行くのじゃ！
Here I go!
はい 見つかっていない異変が23個あるみたい
Okay, it seems there are 23 anomalies that haven't been found.
さすがにあの あれね 23個全回収とかね
Of course, finding all 23...
23個全回収は考えてないけど
I'm not aiming to collect all 23 anomalies, but
体力が許す限り
as long as my energy holds out,
やるのじゃ
I'll keep going.
やらせていただきますのじゃ
I'll give it my all.
覚えてきたし
I've started to memorize them too.
ノースモーキングオッケー
No smoking sign is okay.
1 2 3 4 5 6
うむ
Yep.
のじゃ
All right.
異変なし
No anomaly.
異変なし！
No anomaly!
二周やるより回収の方が早い
It's faster to collect them than to run multiple loops.
じゃ 回収していくのじゃ
So, let's go on a collection run.
変ないのじゃ
Nothing weird.
従業員専用
Employees Only.
地下広場
Underground Concourse.
うん 防犯カメラ
Yeah, security camera...
異変ないのじゃ
No anomaly.
うん
Yeah.
異変見つけるだけじゃからね
Since it's just about finding anomalies...
もう一回クリアしてますからね こちとら
I've already cleared this game once, you know!
こちとらね
As for me,
クリアしてますからね
I've cleared it before!
1！
1!
ナイスなのじゃ
Nice.
行くのじゃ
Off I go.
えーっと
Let's see...
1 2 3 4 5 6 六つありますのじゃ
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, there are six of them.
六つありますのじゃ
There are six of them.
ツルツルじゃないですのじゃ
And it's not slippery.
1 2 3
ちょっと
Let's see...
お顔をね 見せていただいてよろしいか？
Would you mind showing me your face?
普通なのじゃ 普通の顔 わか え 今のは？
It's normal. A normal face... Wait, what was that?
今のはバグ？
Was that a bug?
今のバグ？
今のはわしの おまかん？わしの環境？
Was that on my end? Is it my PC?
なんかノイズ入った ノイズ入ったけど
There was some noise. It made a static sound...
ノイズ入ったけど
There was some noise, but...
ん？これわしの環境？これバグ？
Hmm? Is it my system? Or is this a bug?
これバグか？
Is this a bug?
えーっと
Let's see...
ドッグサロン
Dog salon...
分電盤 分室？
Power distribution room...
司法書士
Judicial Scrivener...
えーっと
Let's see...
ムーブフェス
Move Fes...
防犯カメラ
Security camera...
え 異変ないのじゃ 地下広場
Wait, there's no anomaly. Underground Concourse.
え 異変ない
Wait, no anomaly?
異変ない
No anomaly.
え 異変ないままクリアする感じなのじゃ？
Wait, am I going to clear it with no anomalies at all?
異変ないままクリアする感じなのじゃ？
Am I going to clear it with no anomalies at all?
ないのじゃ
There really is none.
よいしょ
There we go.
2！
2!
なんか
Somehow,
今になって
only now...
ご利益担当が
my blessing-bringing self...
花開く
is starting to bloom.
ね わしの わしのパソコンが良くなかったっぽいんじゃわしのパソコンね ずっとね良くないからの
See, it seems like my PC was just performing badly.
わしのパソコンね ずっとね良くないからの
My PC has always been in a bad state,
ラグかったりしとるからの 1 2 3 4 5 6
and always lags. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
ドアも三つある
there are three doors too.
ノースモーキングおっケー
No smoking sign is okay.
ふむふむ
Hmm, hmm...
エイト歯科おっケー つるつるじゃない
Eight Dental is okay, and it's not slippery.
うん ふんふん
Yeah, hmm...
おじさん？
What about the man?
おじさん わしのこと見てない
The man is not looking at me.
背中とかもオッケーなのじゃ
And his back looks okay as well.
オッケーのじゃ
It's all okay.
えーっと エイト
Let's see, Eight...
アルバイト
Part-time job...
ニューオープン
New Open...
順番とかも 特に変わりなく
The order and everything hasn't changed,
オッケーですのじゃ
so it's okay.
ふむふむ
Hmm, hmm...
ムーブフェス
Move Fes...
防犯カメラOK
Security camera, okay.
従業員専用
Staff Only.
のじゃ？
Huh?
分電盤室
Electrical room.
のじゃ！
Whoa!
うう、の、のじゃ。なんか...
Oof... Oh no... Something...
なんか、なんか、なんか、なんかいた！
Something... something... something... someone was there!
はっ、怖い。怖い。怖い。
Ah! So scary... so scary... so scary.
可愛くない声出るとか言わないでほしいのじゃ！う、のじゃ！のじゃのじゃのじゃ。
Don't say I'm making uncute sounds! Ah, seriously! Come on!
気をつけよう。やっぱ人間に「可愛い」って思ってもらいたいから、気をつけよう。
Let's be careful. Since I want humans to think I'm cute, I'll be careful.
人間に「可愛い」と思ってもらいたいから、き、気をつけよう、のじゃ。
Because I want humans to think I'm cute, I-I'll be careful, yes.
頑張って人間に「可愛い」って思ってもらうと頑張ってるのに...
Even though I'm trying so hard to get humans to think I'm cute...
き、気をつけよう。びっくりしないように。びっくりしないようにしよう、のじゃ。
L-Let's be careful. So I don't get startled. I'll make sure not to be startled.
うーん、禁煙、No Smoking, OK.
Hmm, "No Smoking" is okay.
1、2、3、4、5、6、OK？ドア3つある。ドア3つある。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay? There are three doors. Three doors.
えっと、おじさん、おじさんね。私のこと見てない。
Let's see, the man... He's not looking at me.
興味なさそう。後ろ向いてる。OK.
He doesn't seem interested. He's facing away. Okay.
よし、よし、よし... オープン！
Alright, alright, alright... Open!
バイト募集、ツルツルじゃない？
Job recruitment... Is the floor not slippery?
1、2、3... のじゃ。
1, 2, 3... Yep.
うん、うん、うん、うん。分電盤室、OK.
Right, right, right, right. Electrical room, okay.
えー、司法書士OK。司法書士OK。メイクアップOK。
Let's see, judicial scrivener is okay. Judicial scrivener okay. Makeup okay.
えーっと、MOVEFES OK。防犯カメラOK。え、何も無くね？
Let's see, MOVEFES is okay. Security camera okay. Huh, there's nothing wrong?
上も大丈夫。床も？
The ceiling is fine too. The floor?
床も大丈夫。うん。消火栓もOKなのじゃ。
The floor is fine too. Yeah. Fire hydrant is also okay.
うん。ないの？異変。ないのじゃ。
Yeah. No anomalies? There are none.
ないのじゃ。ないのじゃ。
There are none. None.
4！なんか、すごいスムーズ。
4! This is going really smoothly.
スムーズですのじゃ。
It's super smooth.
スムーズですのじゃ。のじゃ。
1、2、3、4、5、6。なんか数が減るとかはあんまないんじゃな。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. There doesn't seem to be anything like things decreasing.
ドアの数が減る的なのはあんまりないんじゃな。No smoking OK、出口OK。
Like doors decreasing in number, that doesn't really happen. No smoking okay, exit okay.
床ツルツルじゃない？エイト歯科OK。
The floor isn't slippery? Eight Dental is okay.
そして、ちょっとおじさん、おぬしをしっかりと。
And now, let's keep a close eye on this man.
おじさんも何もないね。背中OKですのじゃ。
Nothing wrong with him either. His back looks okay.
ふむふむ。エイト歯科、アルバイトOK。
Uh-huh. Eight Dental, part-time job okay.
オープンOK、分電盤室OK。
Open is okay, electrical room is okay.
司法書士OK、メイクアップOK。
Judicial scrivener is okay, makeup okay.
メイクアップOK、MOVEFES OK、防犯カメラOK。
Makeup okay, MOVEFES okay, security camera okay.
そして、上を見る。「地下広場」OK。
And then, look up. Concourse is okay.
ふん、ふん、ふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
何も無いの？異変。OKなのじゃ。
No anomalies? Everything is okay.
うん、うん、うん、うん。見た。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I looked.
もう一回後ろ振り向く。振り向くね。うん。OKなのじゃ！
I'll look back one more time. Turning around. Yes. Everything's okay!
よし、よし、よし。進むのじゃー！
Good, good, good. Moving forward!
5！5なのじゃー！
5! It's 5!
よし。もう1回クリアしてますからね、私。私はね、1回クリアしてますからね、もう大体もう大丈夫ですのじゃ。
Alright. I've already cleared this once, you know. I've cleared it once, so I'm mostly fine.
下OK。つるつるじゃないOK？禁煙、No Smoking OK。
Floor okay. No slippery spots okay? No Smoking okay.
エイト歯科OK、アルバイトOK。
Eight Dental okay, part-time job okay.
おじさん、おじさん私のこと別に見てない。
The man, he isn't really looking at me.
うん、OK、OK、OK。
Yeah, okay, okay, okay.
あれ？え、ドア1個ない！え、ドア1個ない！
Huh? Wait, there's a door missing! Wait, a door is missing!
ドア1、2、3じゃったのに、ドアが1個ない！ドア1個ない！
There should be doors 1, 2, and 3, but there's a door missing! A door is missing!
ドア1個ない！ドア1個ない。
A door is missing! A door is missing.
やっぱ無くなる系もちゃんとあるんじゃな。3つあったのに。分電盤室がないのじゃ。分電盤室が。
So there really are things that disappear. There were three before. The electrical room is gone. The electrical room...
分電盤室ない。
No electrical room.
行くのじゃ！
Let's go!
1、2、3...
1, 2, 3...
いちにさん、いちにさんしごーろく
1, 2, 3... 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
ドアはあるの？
Are there doors?
ノースモーキング。ツルツルでもないのじゃ。
No smoking. It's not smooth either.
エイト歯科？
Eight Dental Clinic?
ふむふむ。
Hmm, okay.
おじさん？
Mister?
おじさん別にわしのこと見てこない。
He's not really looking at me.
普通のおじさんなのじゃ。
Just a normal mister.
うん、普通ですのじゃ。
Yeah, he is normal.
アルバイトオッケー？
Part-time job okay?
お部屋オッケー？
Room okay?
ズイ。うん、順番も別におかしいとこないのじゃ。
ZUI. Yeah, the order is also not weird.
順番もおかしいとこなーし。
Order is not weird.
天井もおかしいとこなーし。
Ceiling is also not weird.
下も、床もおかしいことなーし。
Bottom, floor is also not weird.
ないの？従業員専用。
None? Employees only.
ないの？
None?
なーし。
None.
え、なんかさっきより簡単なのじゃ。
Eh, somehow it's easier than before.
さっきより簡単なのじゃ。
It's easier than before.
ななー！
Seven!
セブンなのじゃ！
It's seven!
え、もうクリアしちゃうけど。
Eh, I'm already about to clear it.
わしクリアしちゃうけどいいの？
I'm going to clear it, is that okay?
ちら。
*Peek*
え、1 2 3 ドアなし。1 2 3 4 5 6 オッケー。
Eh, 1, 2, 3, no doors. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
よし。
All right.
数はオッケー。
Count is okay.
ノースモーキング？
No smoking?
ツルツルじゃない？
Not smooth?
おじさん見てるか。
Is mister looking?
おじさん別にわしのこと興味ないみたい。
This mister doesn't seem interested in me.
このおじさんは。
For this mister.
背中オッケー？
Back side okay?
背中オッケー。エイト歯科？
Back side okay. Eight Dental Clinic?
アルバイト？
Part-time job?
オープン？
Open?
分電盤室？
Distribution board room?
天井とかも特にないよね？天井とかも特にない？
Nothing unusual on the ceiling, right? Nothing on the ceiling?
地下広場平気？
Concourse is fine?
うん、ふむふむ。
Yeah, hmm.
ないの？異変出ないの？
Nothing? No anomalies?
異変ないのじゃ。
No anomalies.
クリアしちゃうよ、わし。いいの？
I'm going to clear it. Is that okay?
わしクリアしちゃっていいの？
Can I just clear it?
はちー！
Eight!
なんかするっと行けちゃった。1回目全然あれじゃったのに、するっと行けちゃった。
I managed to go through smoothly. Even though the first time was like that, I went through easily.
いいの？するっと行けちゃって。
Is it okay that I went through so smoothly?
ラッキーなのじゃ。
That's lucky.
行くのじゃ。
Let's go.
よいしょ、よいしょ。のじゃ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Noja.
え？
Eh?
見て、おぬしら。なんか映ってる。向こうの壁になんか映ってる。
Look, you guys. Something's reflecting. There's something reflecting on the wall over there.
わし見える。
I can see it.
なんかいる。ねぇ、なんか、なんか映ってる。
Something's there. Hey, something, something is reflecting.
なんか映ってる。
Something is reflecting.
なんかめっちゃカメレオンみたいなの映ってる。
Something like a giant chameleon is reflecting.
め、めっちゃカメレオンみたいなの映ってる。
A super chameleon-like thing is reflecting.
見えない？おぬしら見えない？見せてあげようか。
Can't you see it? You guys can't see? Shall I show you?
ほら。
See.
ほら。なんか体あるよ。体あるのじゃ。
See. There's a body. It has a body.
体ある。
It has a body.
ほら、見て。
Look, see.
体ある。
It has a body.
体あるよ。
It has a body!
怖い、怖い。
Scary, scary.
怖いのじゃ。
It's scary.
怖い。
Scary.
びっくりしたのじゃ。
I was startled.
怖い。
Scary.
え、近づいた方がいい？よく見た方がいい？
Eh, should I get closer? Should I look closely?
ま、クリアしてるし、一回近づいてみるか。
Well, since I've cleared it, let's try getting closer once.
わしクリアしてるしな。
I've already cleared it anyway.
行ったね。
I went.
え、こういう人ってさ、裸ん坊なのかな？
Eh, is this kind of person naked?
裸ん坊で色塗ってるのかな？協力者がいるのかな？
Are they naked and painted? Is there an accomplice?
ギャー！
AHH!
お、追いかけてくる！な、な、何なのじゃ！
It's chasing me! Wh-What is that!
な、な、何なのじゃ！
Wh-What is that!
おじゃー！
Oja-!
びっくりした！びっくりした！
That startled me! That startled me!
ちか、近づくと、近づくと、近づくと追いかけてくるのじゃ！
If, if you get close, if you get close, if you get close, it chases you!
近づくと追いかけてくるのじゃ。
It chases you if you get close.
びっくりした。びっくりした、びっくりした。
I was startled. Startled, startled.
チェイシングなのじゃ！
It's chasing!
追いかけっこなのじゃ。え、あれ捕まってたら、あれ捕まってたらどうなってた？
It's a chase game. Eh, what if I got caught by that? What would have happened if I got caught by that?
あれ捕まってたらどうなってた？
What would have happened if I got caught?
あれ捕まってたらどうなってたのじゃ？
What would have happened if I got caught by that?
びっくりした！びっくりした！
I was startled! I was startled!
初見で逃げ切った人初めて見た？みんな逃げないの？
First time seeing someone escape on their first try? Doesn't everyone run away?
みんな、配信者的にはぶつかるのが正解？
Is colliding with it the correct answer for streamers?
配信者的にぶつかった方が美味しかったのじゃ？
For streamers, would it have been better to collide with it?
ちょっとあれかな、新人じゃの。
Maybe I'm a rookie.
ちょ、配信者的にはぶつかってた方が美味しかったかもしれん。
Hmm, for a streamer, it might have been better if I had collided.
怖かったのじゃ。こ、怖すぎて...
It was scary. It-It was too scary...
怖すぎ て
It was too scary...
怖すぎて逃げちゃったのじゃ
I got too scared and ran away.
びっくりしたのじゃ
It really surprised me.
びっくりしましたのじゃ
It really startled me.
ふぅ にしてもびっくりした
Phew, that really scared me though.
よし
Alright.
よし よし よし よし よし よし
Alright, alright, alright.
びっくりしたのじゃ 行くのじゃ
That shocked me. Let's go.
ん？
Huh?
どういうこと？
What does this mean?
なんで逆なの？
Why is it reversed?
なんで逆なのじゃ？
Why is it going backward?
まち ん？
Wait... Huh?
のじゃ？
What?
What's going on?
あれ？ なんか0になってる！
Wait! It went back to 0!
え なんか0になってる なんで？
It's back to 0! Why?
のじゃ？
What?
なんか0になってる
It went back to 0.
んー？
Hmm?
あ
Ah.
あの 追っかけてくる人が
The guy who was chasing me...
追っかけてくる人が怖すぎて
He was so scary...
のじゃ
so...
逃げすぎたのじゃ
I ran back too far.
逃げすぎちゃった
I ran too far back!
逃げすぎちゃった！
I ran too far!
怖かったのじゃ だって
But I was scared!
だって だって 追っかけ回されるの怖いのじゃん
I mean, anyone would be scared of being chased!
おっ 追っかけ回されるの怖いから逃げる 普通逃げるのじゃ
Being chased is scary, so of course you'd run!
びっくりした 床はオッケー？
That shocked me. Is the floor okay?
1 2 3 1 2 3 4 5 6 オッケー
1, 2, 3... 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, okay.
びっくりした
That was surprising.
おじさん見る
Let's look at the man.
おじさんオッケー？ 私のこと見てない？
Is he okay? Is he looking at me?
私のこと見てない オッケー
He's not looking at me. Okay.
よし よし よし よし アルバイト
Alright. Part-time job poster is here.
サロン ドッグサロン
Dog salon poster is here.
天井もオッケー？
Is the ceiling okay?
分電盤オッケー？
Electrical box okay?
うん
Yeah.
司法書士オッケー？
Judicial scrivener poster okay?
なんかなさそうじゃの
Seems like nothing is wrong.
地下広場 オッケー
Concourse sign is okay.
うん うん うん
Yeah, yeah.
防犯カメラ作動中
"Security camera in operation" is there.
なさそう 異変なし
Nothing's wrong. No anomalies.
異変なし
No anomalies.
No anomalies here.
よし
Alright.
えーっと
Let's see...
通路オッケー？
Corridor is okay?
天井オッケー
Ceiling is okay.
禁煙オッケー
No smoking sign is okay.
エイト歯科医院 アルバイトオッケー
Eight Dental Clinic and part-time job are okay.
分電盤もオッケー？
Is the electrical box okay too?
うん
Yeah.
おじさんも見ます
Let's check the man too.
おじさんオッケーなのじゃ
Is he okay?
うん おじさんもオッケーそう
Yeah, the man seems okay too.
ポスターもオッケー？
Are the posters okay?
司法書士オッケー 順番も問題ないのじゃ
Judicial scrivener is okay. The order is correct too.
ドアも3つ
Three doors here too.
うん 防犯カメラ
Yeah, security camera.
従業員専用
Staff only door.
清掃 うん 同じ
Janitor... yeah, it's the same.
上にもなさそうじゃの
Nothing on the ceiling either.
よし オッケー
Alright, okay.
行くのじゃ！
Let's go!
うん うん うん
Yeah, yeah.
あと20個異変あるって？
"There are 20 anomalies left"?
20個
20.
よし
Alright.
え？
Eh?
色が違う
The color is different.
The color is different!
真っ赤なのじゃ
It's bright red!
これくらい分かりやすかったらね
If only they were always this obvious.
わしが一番最初にこのゲーム遊んだ時もこれくらい分かりやすくさ
If it was this easy when I first played this game...
初回でこれやってくれたらわしだってね ゲーム性分かった
and they showed me this first, I would've understood the gameplay immediately!
1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3 うん 数問題なし
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6... 1, 2, 3. Yeah, the numbers are correct.
ノー・スモーキング
No smoking sign.
床ツルツルじゃない？
Is the floor slippery?
うん
Yeah.
エイト歯科医院オッケー
Eight Dental Clinic is okay.
おじさんもどうかの？
What about the man?
おじさん大丈夫？
Is he okay?
出口8？
Exit 8?
分電盤室？
Electrical box room?
うん ZUI
Yeah, Zui.
順番も問題ないのじゃ
The order is correct too.
順番も問題ない
The order is correct.
ムーブフェス
Move Fes poster.
カメラ
Camera is there.
ドア
Doors...
問題なさそう
Seems like nothing's wrong.
問題なさそうなのじゃ
Seems like nothing is wrong.
うん 天井も 天井も大丈夫
Yeah, the ceiling is okay too.
よし
Alright.
進む！
Let's move on!
4！ 4なのじゃ！
4! It's Exit 4!
うん
Yeah.
まだまだいけるのじゃ
I can keep going.
あと19個
19 left.
よいしょ よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho...
ちら
Peek.
1 2 3 4 5 6ある ドアも3つある
There are 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 posters. There are three doors too.
よし
Okay.
床もツルツルじゃない
The floor isn't slippery either.
ノー・スモーキング オッケー
No smoking, okay.
え、歯科医院、アルバイト、オッケー。
Eh, dental clinic, part-time job, okay.
おじさん、わし見とるな。
That man is looking at me.
おじさん、わしのこと見とるな。
That man is staring at me.
おじさん、わしめっちゃ見とるな。
He's really staring at me.
逃げる。
Run away!
ファイブ！
Five!
これが、見てくるおじさん。
So this is the staring man.
めっちゃ見られた。
He stared at me so much.
見られたのじゃ。
I was stared at.
興味あるのかね、わしに。
Is he interested in me?
1、2、3、4、5、6、つるつるじゃない。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6... Not slippery.
1、2、3、ドアオッケー。
1, 2, 3, doors are okay.
ノースモーキング。
No smoking.
ええと、エイト歯科医院。
Let's see, Eight Dental Clinic.
分電盤室。
Distribution Board Room.
ふむふむ。
Hmm, hmm.
おじさんもう見て来なくなっちゃった。わしのこと嫌いになった？
The man stopped looking at me. Does he hate me now?
わしのことどうでもよくなっちゃったのじゃ？
Does he not care about me anymore?
好きの反対は無関心なのじゃ。
The opposite of love is indifference.
悲しいの。
How sad.
切ないの。
How painful.
でも人間は心移りするもの。
But humans change their minds.
わしにそれに対してとやかく言うことはできねえですのじゃ。
I have no right to complain about that.
うむ。異変はなさそうかな？天井、床。うん、大丈夫。
Hmm, no anomalies? Ceiling, floor... Yeah, okay.
よし、ない！
All right, none!
ロク！シックスなのじゃ！
Six! It's six!
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
行くのじゃ！
Let's go!
ちら。
Peek.
1、2、3、4、5、6。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
1、2、3、ドアの数とかオッケー。床もオッケー。
1, 2, 3, the number of doors is okay. Floor is okay.
ノースモーキング。
No smoking.
エイト歯科医院。
Eight Dental Clinic.
アルバイト募集。
Part-time job recruitment.
おじさん見る。おじさん？おじさん見た。
The man looks. Mister? The mister looked.
背中もオッケー。
His back is okay too.
オープン、司法書士。
Open, judicial scrivener...
おおお！異変！なんじゃ？なんじゃ？なんじゃ？なんじゃ？
Oh oh oh! An anomaly! What is it? What is it?
走れないの？走れないの？
Can't I run? Can't I run?
走る走る走る走る走る走る走る走る。
Running running running running...
ふう、びっくりした。
Phew, that scared me.
あんまり怖い音出すのやめるのじゃ。
Please stop making such scary sounds.
びっくりした。ちかちかするの怖いのじゃ。
That scared me. Flickering is so scary.
1、2、3、4、5、6。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
1、2、3、禁煙ノースモーキング。床つるつるじゃない。
1, 2, 3, no smoking. The floor isn't slippery.
うん、天井。ん？曲がってる！曲がってるのじゃ！
Yeah, ceiling... Hm? It's bent! It's bent!
光が曲がってる！
The light is bent!
エイト！
Eight!
8。
Eight.
異変じゃの。
It's an anomaly.
おお、これはわかりやすい。
Oh, this one is very obvious.
これはわかりやすく恐ろしいの。
This is clearly terrifying.
怖いのじゃ。
It's scary.
怖い。
Scary.
よしよしよしよし。
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
あんま怖くないの頼みたいんじゃが。
I'd like to request something not so scary though...
ええ、1、2、3、4、5、6。
Yeah, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
1、2、3。
1, 2, 3.
うむ。ノースモーキング。床つるつるじゃない。
Hmm. No smoking. Floor isn't slippery.
ふむ、ふむ、ふむ。エイト歯科医院。
Hmm, hmm, hmm. Eight Dental Clinic.
アルバイト。
Part-time job.
おじさん、おじさんの異変もなし。
Mister, no anomaly with him either.
後ろも大丈夫？
Is behind me okay too?
うん。
Yeah.
ニューオープン。
New Open.
司法書士。
Judicial scrivener.
メイクアップ、ムーブフェス。
Makeup... Move Fes.
これクリアしちゃうんじゃない？
Won't I clear this?
うん、地下広場。
Yeah, underground plaza.
これクリアしちゃうんじゃない？うん。
Won't I clear this? Yeah.
クリアーー！
Cleared!
2回目クリアなのじゃ！
Cleared for the second time!
異変あんま見つかんないの。
I didn't find many anomalies.
異変が思ったより...
Anomalies were... more than I thought...
やっぱね、ご利益担当すぎてね
As expected, I'm in charge of blessings...
ちょっと運がね、よすぎるのじゃ。
...so my luck is a little too good.
運がよすぎて見つけまくっちゃうのじゃ。
My luck is so good that I keep finding them easily.
あんま異変なかった。
There weren't many anomalies.
わしの強運さ。
That's my great luck.
もっかい行ってみるのじゃ。
Let's try going one more time.
あと18？
18 more left?
18とか17とか...
Like, 18 or 17...
うん、それぐらいな気がする。
Yeah, I feel like it's around that.
それぐらいな気がするけど、見つかんないの。
I feel like it's around that, but I can't find them.
RTA？
An RTA?
RTAってできるのじゃ？
Can we do an RTA?
気持ちだけ、気持ちだけね。
Just the mindset, just the mindset, okay?
RTAの気持ちでやってみよう。
Let's try playing with an RTA mindset.
ぢぢぢぢぢぢ
Di-di-di-di-di-di...
RTA勢、しゃ、しゃ
RTA runner mode! Swish, swish...
しゃ、しゃ
Swish, swish...
しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ
Swish, swish, swish, swish...
お、RTA勢っぽい動き。
Oh, that's like an RTA runner's movement!
しゃしゃしゃしゃしゃしゃ
Swish, swish, swish, swish, swish!
1！
One!
RTA勢っぽい動きをしてみた。
I tried moving like an RTA runner.
どうじゃ？
How was that?
しゃしゃしゃしゃ、しゃ、しゃ
Swish, swish, swish...
これで普通に見落としそうなんじゃが。
I feel like I'd easily miss things like this.
普通に見落としそうなんじゃが、司法書士。
I feel like I'd easily miss things... judicial scrivener.
1、2、3。
One, two, three.
うん、1、2、3、大丈夫。
Yeah, one, two, three, looks fine.
しゃ、しゃ
Swish, swish...
え、ない？
Huh? There's none?
異変ないのじゃ？
Are there no anomalies?
異変ない！
No anomalies!
2！
Two!
異変ない！
No anomalies!
しゃ、ノースモーキング。床大丈夫？
Swish. No smoking. Floor is fine?
ふむふむ、ふむふむ。異変ない。
Hmm, hmm... no anomalies.
ズイ。
Zui...
のじゃのじゃ。1、2、3、4、5、6。
I see. One, two, three, four, five, six.
うん、異変ないの。
Yeah, no anomalies.
ない。のじゃ。のじゃのじゃ。
None. I see. Indeed, indeed.
うーん、なさそう。
Hmm, doesn't seem like it.
ない！
None!
もう一回見る。
Let me look again.
ない！
None!
3！
Three!
てててててててて
Te-te-te-te-te-te...
ふむ。
Hmm.
床平気？禁煙平気？1、2、3、4、5、6、1、2、3。うん。
Floor is fine? No smoking fine? 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3. Yeah.
ない。ない。
None. None.
おじさん、おじさんこんなデカかったっけ？
Mister, was the man always this big?
おじさんこんなデカかった？デカくないのじゃ？
Was the man always this big? Isn't he bigger?
覚えてないけど、こんなデカくなかった気がする。
I don't remember, but I feel like he wasn't this big.
4！
Four!
したたたたたたた
Shi-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta...
のじゃのじゃ。床つるつる？
I see. Is the floor slippery?
ある...。だよね、おじさんのサイズだよね。
There's... Right, he's his normal size.
よいしょよいしょ。1、2、3、4、5、6、うん。
Yoisho, yoisho. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. Yeah.
異変ないの？
No anomalies?
ない。
None.
ないのじゃ！
There's none!
ててててててて
Te-te-te-te-te-te...
5なのじゃ！
It's five!
よいしょ！
Yoisho!
1、2、3、4、5、6、1、1、2、3。うん、床オッケー。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 1, 2, 3. Yeah, floor is okay.
天井も大丈夫そう。
The ceiling seems fine too.
1、エイト歯科。2、アルバイト募集。うん。3、オープン。
1, Eight Dental. 2, part-time job recruitment, yeah. 3, open.
分電盤室、うん。
Distribution board room, yeah.
おじさん見るのじゃ。
Let's look at the man.
おじさんも、ない。地下広場。
Nothing with the man either. Concourse.
ないのじゃ、異変。え、なんでこんなないの？
There are no anomalies. Huh, why are there none?
なんでこんなないのじゃ？
Why are there so few?
ない！
None!
6！
Six!
よいしょ！
Yoisho!
1、2、3、4,、5、6、禁煙。つるつるじゃない。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, no smoking. Not slippery.
うん、エイト歯科医院。1、2、3部屋ある。
Yeah, Eight Dental Clinic. There are 1, 2, 3 rooms.
2、アルバイト募集、オッケー。うん。順番も合ってる。
2, part-time job recruitment, okay. Yeah. The order is correct too.
おじさん。おじさんも別に異変なし。
The man. No anomalies with the man either.
屋上もない。1、2。
No roof either. 1, 2.
ない。
None.
異変ない。あ、
No anomalies. Oh,
ある！これ点いてなかった！戻る戻る戻る戻る！
There is one! This light wasn't on! Go back, go back, go back!
点いてなかった。ある！
It wasn't on. There is one!
のじゃ！
Indeed!
7！
Seven!
うん、よいしょ。
Yeah, yoisho.
禁煙、ノースモーキング、床つるつるじゃない。1、2、3、4、5、6、1、2、3。
No smoking, no smoking, floor is not slippery. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3.
ドアの数は大丈夫なのじゃ。1、2、3。
The number of doors is fine. 1, 2, 3.
分電盤室、うん。
Distribution board room, yeah.
おじさん見る。おじさん。
Look at the man. The man.
うん、おじさんも異変なし。
Yeah, no anomalies with the man either.
なし。
None.
1、2、3、4、5、6。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
部屋も特に異常なし。
The rooms have no abnormalities either.
うーん、ないのじゃ。
Hmm, there are none.
ない！ないのじゃ！
None! There are none!
8！
Eight!
あと何個？
How many more left?
13個。あんま見つかんないのじゃ。よいしょ。
13. I can't really find them. Yoisho.
えー、1、2、3、4、5、6、うん。1、2、3、扉の数問題なし。禁煙。
Uh, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, yeah. 1, 2, 3, no issue with the number of doors. No smoking.
床つるつるじゃない。
Floor is not slippery.
天井大丈夫。
Ceiling is fine.
エイト歯科医院。
Eight Dental Clinic.
アルバイト募集
Part-time job hiring...
分電盤室
...distribution board room...
おじさんは
The mister...
おじさんも大丈夫
...is also fine.
オープン　うん
"Open." Yep.
なさげ
Looks like nothing.
従業員専用
"Staff Only."
ふんふんふんふん
Hmm, okay, okay.
異変なさげ
No anomalies here.
うん
Yeah.
後ろから見ても大丈夫
Looking from behind, it's also fine.
下も、うん
The floor too, yeah.
ない
Nothing!
えっ、あったの？
Eh? There was one?
なに？
What was it?
あったっぽい
Seems like there was one!
何が異変だったんじゃろう？
I wonder what the anomaly was?
なんじゃろ？
What could it be?
あ、ここじゃない？
Ah, isn't it here?
防犯カメラ作動中がここじゃなかった！
The "Security camera in operation" sign wasn't here!
あーー
Ahhh...
盲点でしたのじゃ
It was a blind spot...
...a blind spot indeed.
もっと異変見つけるのじゃ！
I must find more anomalies!
よいしょ　でも怖くなくなってきた
Alright, but I'm not scared anymore.
1 1 2 3 1 1 1 2 3 4 5 6
床平気
Floor is fine.
確かにポスターなかったな
Indeed there were no posters.
その辺も覚えなきゃ　地下広場
I need to memorize those too. "Concourse."
おじさん
The mister...
のじゃ
...is fine.
うん　おじさんも異変なし
Yeah, the mister has no anomalies either.
うん　大丈夫そう
Yeah, looks fine.
大丈夫そう！
Looks fine!
1！
1!
のじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃのじゃ！
Noja noja noja noja!
えー 1 2 3 4 5 6 床平気
Let's see, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6... Floor is fine.
禁煙平気
"No Smoking" is fine.
1 2 3 ドア平気
1, 2, 3... Doors are fine.
1 2 3 4
5 6
おじさんも平気
The mister is also fine.
えっ　止まった？
Eh, did he stop?
えっ えっ 何？絶対に追いかけてる！
Eh, eh, what?! He's definitely chasing me!
絶対に追いかけてきてる！
He's definitely coming after me!
なんかおじさん止まった！おじさん止まったのじゃ！
The mister stopped! The mister stopped!
のじゃーー！
Nojaaa!
はい　逃げる！
Okay, run!
巻いていく！
Lose him!
はぁ 止まるの？止まる系？
*phew* Stopping? He's the type that stops?
そういうのじゃね　のじゃのじゃのじゃ
So that's how it is... noja noja noja.
禁煙 1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3
"No Smoking." 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6... 1, 2, 3.
大丈夫
Fine.
うん　つるつるでもないね　つるつるでもない
Yeah, it's not slippery either. Not slippery.
おじさんは
The mister...
止まらない
...isn't stopping.
天井もない
Nothing on the ceiling either.
ドアノブも大丈夫
Door knobs are also fine.
うん　何もなし
Yeah, nothing.
のじゃ　3！
Noja, 3!
あと何個？
How many left?
あと12個あるのじゃ！
There are still 12 left!
よいしょ
Alright.
1 2 3
床つるつるじゃない 1 2 3 4 5 6
Floor isn't slippery. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
番号大丈夫　うん　ズイ
Numbers are fine. Yep, "Zui."
順番も合ってる
The order is also correct.
うん　おじさん
Yeah, the mister...
うん　大丈夫
...yeah, is fine.
ドアノブも大丈夫
Door knobs are also fine.
うん
Yeah.
なさそう
Seems like nothing.
ない！
Nothing!
4！
4!
1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3 ドアの数も問題なし
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3... Number of doors is also fine.
床平気？
Floor fine?
後ろも平気　地下広場
Behind is also fine. "Concourse."
おじさん
The mister...
おじさんも平気
...is also fine.
ないの？
Nothing here?
おるおるおるおる！お前お前お前！お前お前お前！お前ーー！
Ah, there is, there is! You, you, you! You!
動いてるのじゃーー！
They are moving!
異変なのじゃーー！
It's an anomaly!
よし 1 2 3 4 5 6
Alright. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
うわああああ！のじゃのじゃのじゃ！暗くなるの嫌い！暗くなるの嫌いなのじゃ！
AHHH! Noja noja noja! I hate when it gets dark! I hate it!
6！
6!
うぅ　びっくりしたー
Ugh, that scared me...
10個、怖い
10 left... It's scary...
のじゃ
...noja.
びっくり系が急に現れる感じね　なるほどね　うん　禁煙
So jump scares suddenly appear like that. I see. Okay, "No Smoking."
床つるつるじゃない 1 2 3 4 5 6
Floor isn't slippery. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
えっと 1 2 3
Let's see... 1, 2, 3.
おじさんチェック
Mister check...
...mister check...
おじさんチェックおっけー
...mister check OK.
怖かったー
That was scary...
でもなんか　これはまた怪しいじゃの
But somehow... this seems suspicious again.
よいしょ
Yoisho.
ない　異変なーし
Nothing. No anomalies!
異変なーし！
No anomalies!
7！
7!
よし
Alright.
1 2 3 4 5 6
うむ
Hmm.
床おっけー　天井もおっけー
Floor OK, ceiling also OK.
1 2 3
おじさんチェック入るのじゃ
Mister check starting...
おじさん　おっけー
...mister... OK.
司法書士
"Judicial Scrivener."
ない　なさげ
None. Seems like nothing.
ノーベフェス
Novefes.
天井も見るのじゃ
I should look at the ceiling too.
天井もない
Nothing on the ceiling either.
ん、ん、ん
Mm-hmm.
従業員専用、おけ？
Employee only, okay?
うん
Yep.
ないのー
Nothing.
うん
Hmm.
なさげ
Seems like there's nothing.
のじゃー！８！エイトエイトエイト！
Noja! 8! Eight, eight, eight!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
1, 2, 3.
数はオッケー。ツルツルじゃない？
The count is okay. It's not slippery, right?
ツルツルじゃない？エイト歯科
Not slippery, right? Eight dental clinic...
２...
Two...
うん、オッケー
Yep, okay.
オッケー。おじさんチェック入るのじゃ。
Okay. Let's do the old man check.
おじさんもオッケー。地下広場。
The old man is also okay. Concourse...
はーはーはーはー
Aha...
おっ
Oh.
違うポスター！
A different poster!
違うポスターなのじゃー！
It's a different poster, noja!
のじゃー！
Noja!
可愛いウサギのポスターだったのじゃ。
It was a cute rabbit poster, noja.
１２３４５６、１２３、うん。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. Yep.
床もツルツルじゃない？
The floor isn't slippery either, right?
１、２、３...
1, 2, 3...
おじさんチェック入るのじゃ。おじさん？
Time for the old man check, noja. Old man?
のじゃー、のじゃー。
Noja, noja.
うん、おじさんは大丈夫。
Yep, the old man is fine.
あれもないんじゃないか？
Doesn't seem like there's anything there either.
うん。
Yep.
ない。
Nothing.
ない！
Nothing!
クリアー！
Clear!
のじゃー！
Noja!
これ全部回収できる予感するのじゃ。まだ９時じゃし。
I feel like we can collect everything this time, noja. It's only 9:00.
まだ９時じゃし。
It's still 9:00.
もっかい行くのじゃ！
We're going in again, noja!
もっかい回収するのじゃ！
We're going to collect them all again, noja!
なんか、８番出口のプロになれる気がしてきたのじゃ。
Somehow, I feel like I'm becoming a professional at Exit 8, noja.
わし１回きりの短期記憶苦手じゃけど、
Even though I'm usually bad at short-term memory...
これだけ何回も見たらかすがに覚えられる気がしてきましたのじゃ。
seeing it this many times makes me feel like I can finally remember it, noja.
いけるのじゃ。
I can do this.
うん。
Yeah.
確かにクリアしないで、異変探ししてもいいかも。
Indeed, maybe it's fine to look for anomalies without clearing.
確かに、確かに。
True, true.
ベテランなのじゃ。
Like a veteran, noja.
あのね、わしね、ゲームあんまり経験がないからね、
You see, since I don't have much experience with games...
ゲーム経験っていうの？あのー、あのー、
game experience or whatever you call it...
あんまりちっちゃい頃とかゲームやらないで育ったから、
I grew up not playing games much when I was little,
そういう意味で、なんじゃろな、
so in that sense...
ゲームやんないで育ったから、あんまりゲームに詳しくない、
since I grew up without playing games, I'm not very familiar with them,
ところはあるんじゃが、
there are aspects like that,
でも、あのー、
but, you know,
よいしょ。
Alright.
やったら慣れる気がするのじゃ。
I feel like I'll get used to it if I play, noja!
やったら慣れそう！
If I play, I'll get used to it!
やったら慣れそうな気がするのじゃ。
I feel like I can get used to it if I play, noja.
行くのじゃー！
Let's go!
おお、異変！
Oh, anomaly!
同じポスター！
The same poster!
のじゃー！
Noja!
よいしょ。
Here we go.
１２３４５６、１２３、ポスターおけ、
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. Poster okay...
あ、ツルツル！
Ah, slippery!
点字ブロックがツルツルなのじゃー！
The yellow braille blocks are slippery, noja!
引き返す！
Turn back!
3.
ん、ん、ん、ん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
１２３４５６、１２３、ドアの数オッケー。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. 1, 2, 3. Door count is okay.
よいしょ。
Alright.
エイト歯科、アルバイト募集、オープン、
Eight dental clinic, recruitment, open...
うん、うん。
Mm-hmm.
おじさんチェック入るのじゃ。
Time to check the old man.
おじさん？
Old man?
おじさん大丈夫。
The old man is fine.
地下広場。
Concourse...
うん、防犯カメラ作動中。
Yeah, security camera in operation.
従業員専用。
Employee-only door.
うん、これも大丈夫なのじゃ。
Yep, this also seems fine, noja.
異変なし。
No anomalies.
異変なーし！
No anomalies!
４！
4!
じゃ、じゃ、じゃ、じゃ。１２３４５６。
Alright, alright, alright. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
１２３４５６。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
２、１、２、３、４...
2, 1, 2, 3, 4...
うん、うん。
Mm-hmm.
おじさん見る？
Should I look at the old man?
おじさんチェック。
Old man check.
おじさんオッケー。
Old man okay.
うん。
Yep.
行くのじゃ。大丈夫そうな気がするけど。
Let's go, noja. I feel like it's fine, though.
大丈夫そう。
Seems fine.
行くのじゃ！異変見つけるのじゃ！
Let's go, noja! Let's find an anomaly, noja!
えーっと、下、床。
So, the floor...
天井、禁煙、１２３４５６。
ceiling, no smoking, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
エイト歯科...
Eight dental clinic...
アルバイト...
Part-time job...
むむ。
Mumu.
おじさん見る。
I'll watch the old guy.
おじさん笑ってね？
Is the old guy smiling?
おじさん笑ってる！
The old guy is smiling!
笑ってる気がするのじゃ！６！
I feel like he's smiling! Six!
おじさん笑ってる。
The old guy is smiling.
１、２、３、４、５、６、禁煙...
One, two, three, four, five, six... No smoking...
あ、反対だ！
Ah, it's backwards!
反対になってるのじゃ！
It's backwards!
看板が反対。
The sign is backwards.
あと５個だって。
Five more left, apparently.
あと５個。
Five more.
うんうん、禁煙、床。
Yep, yep, no smoking, floor.
１、２、３、４、５、６...
One, two, three, four, five, six...
うぎゃー！
Whoa!
何何何何？何この音？
What, what, what, what? What's this sound?
何この音？大きい音？
What is this sound? A loud sound?
大きい音本当にびっくりするから嫌だ。
Loud sounds really scare me, so I hate them.
大きい音本当にびっくりするから嫌なのじゃ。
びっくりした。
That scared me.
大きい音、大きい音怖いのじゃ。
Loud sounds, loud sounds are scary.
バクバクするのじゃ。
My heart is pounding.
１、２、３、４、５、６。
One, two, three, four, five, six.
１、２...
One, two...
うん、確かにキックはデカければデカいほどいいって言ったけど...
Yeah, they say the bigger the kick, the better, but...
そこまでデカくする必要はないのじゃ。
There's no need to make it that loud.
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ない？
Nothing?
ないの？
Is there nothing?
ない。
Nothing.
ゴールしちゃった。
I reached the goal.
次で行けるんじゃない？あと異変４とか...
Can't we make it next time? Maybe 4 anomalies left or something...
あと異変４とかだった気がするのじゃ。から...
I feel like there were 4 anomalies left. So...
だから、そろそろもう全部見つかる気がしますのじゃ。
So, I feel like we'll find all of them soon.
うん。
Yeah.
わかってきた。
I'm starting to get it.
最初はね...
At first...
最初はの、クリアするたびに...
At first, every time I cleared it...
やっと、やっと地上に出れたって...
"Finally, I finally made it to the surface..." I thought.
すごい...
I was so...
嬉しくなってたのに...
...happy, but...
今となっては...
Now...
慣れて怖いの。
I'm used to it, and that's scary.
慣れていくって...
Getting used to it...
フレッシュさがなくなっていくって...
...means the freshness fades away.
切ないの。
It's a bit sad.
切ないことなのじゃ。
It's a sad thing.
のじゃ。うん。
Yes. Yeah.
恐ろしいの... あ、あと４個！
That's scary... Oh, 4 left!
４個ならすぐ見つかるんじゃない？
If there are 4 left, won't we find them quickly?
４個ならすぐ見つかるんじゃない？４個ならね...
If there are 4 left, we should find them quickly. With only 4 left...
のじゃのじゃ。
Indeed, indeed.
おじさんも見るよ。
I'll check the old guy too.
おじさん...
Mr. Old Guy...
おっけー？
Are you okay?
おじさんおっけー。
The old guy is okay.
のじゃのじゃ。
Indeed, indeed.
天井とかもおっけー。
The ceiling is also okay.
おじさーん...
Mr. Old Guuuy...
よいしょ。
Alright.
階段！
Stairs!
階段なのじゃ！
It's the stairs!
あれね、最初登っちゃったやつね、わしが。
Those are the ones I climbed up at the very beginning.
わしが最初登っちゃったやつなのじゃ。
The ones I climbed up first.
１、２、３、４、５、６。
One, two, three, four, five, six.
扉ある？
Is there a door?
おじさん？
The old guy?
おじさん問題なし。従業員専用、問題なし。
The old guy is fine. Staff only, fine.
むむ。階段怖かったのじゃ。
Mumu. The stairs were scary.
登っちゃった階段。
The stairs I climbed up.
よいしょ、１、２、１、２、３、４、５、６。
Alright, one, two, one, two, three, four, five, six.
大丈夫。大丈夫。
Okay. Okay.
おじさん確認。地下広場おっけー。
Checking the old guy. Concourse is okay.
異変ないの？天井も大丈夫。
No anomalies? The ceiling is also fine.
異変ない。
No anomalies.
４！
Four!
なんか明らかに違う。
Something is clearly different.
点字ブロックが違うのじゃ。５！
The tactile paving blocks are different. Five!
点字ブロックが違う。
The tactile paving blocks are different.
禁煙、１、２、３、４、５、６。
No smoking, one, two, three, four, five, six.
のじゃのじゃ。おじさんチェック。
Yes, yes. Checking the old guy.
おじさん大丈夫？おじさん大丈夫。
Old guy is okay? Old guy is okay.
監視カメラもある。
There's a security camera too.
うん。監視カメラもある。
Yeah, there's a security camera too.
大丈夫。６！
We're good. Six!
よいしょ。禁煙、no smoking、１、２、３、１、２、３、４、５、６。
Alright. No smoking, no smoking, one, two, three, one, two, three, four, five, six.
エイト歯科、問題なし、問題なし。
Eight Dental Clinic, no problems, no problems.
問題なし？うん、おじさん。
No problems? Yeah, the old guy.
んー、チェック入る？
Hmm, let's do a check.
おじさんチェックオッケー
Old man check, okay.
ん、大丈夫そう
Hmm, looks fine.
天井も床も…大丈夫！
The ceiling and floor are... okay!
のじゃ！
Noja!
７！
Seven!
うーん
Hmm...
タバコ、ノースモーキング。エイト。１，２，３，４…
Cigarettes, No Smoking. Eight. 1, 2, 3, 4...
おお！なんか怖いポスターになってる
Oh! The poster looks scary!
ポスターが違うのじゃ！
The poster is different, noja!
最後のとこのポスターが違う。８！
The last poster is different. Eight!
えーっと
Let's see...
禁煙。１，２，３。１，２，３，４…１，２，３，４，５，６。
No Smoking. 1, 2, 3... 4... 5, 6.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
１，２，３，４，５，６。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
おじさんの顔がバグってる
The old man's face is bugged!
おじさんの顔がバグってるのじゃ
The old man's face is bugged, noja!
びっくりしたー
That startled me!
すべての異変見つけたって？
Did it say "All anomalies found"?
すべての異変…あ
All anomalies... Ah!
追いかけてきたやついる！
Someone's chasing me!
のじゃー！
Noja!
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
タバコ、床ツルツルじゃない？
Cigarettes... Isn't the floor shiny?
１、２、３，４，５，６
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
上見る、ドア
Looking up... Doors.
おじさん
Old man.
防犯カメラ
Security camera.
大丈夫そうかな？
Is everything okay?
ゴールなのじゃー！
It's the goal, noja!
コンプもしたのじゃー！
I completed everything, noja!
やったのじゃー！
I did it, noja!
うん
Yeah.
コンプしましたのじゃ
I completed it, noja.
クリアなのじゃー！
I cleared it, noja!
ありがとうなのじゃー！
Thank you so much, noja!
わしのね、ご利益パワーでコンプして
With my divine blessing power, I completed it...
見せましたのじゃー！
...and showed you, noja!
慣れって怖いのう
Getting used to things is scary, isn't it?
すごい？早い？
Was it amazing? Fast?
すごかったら高評価ボタン押して！
If it was awesome, hit that like button!
高評価してほしいのじゃー！
I want you to leave a like, noja!
おねがいなのじゃー！
Please, noja!
うむ
Hmm.
なかなか頑張りましたのじゃ
I worked pretty hard, noja.
ん
Mm.
やったのじゃ
I did it, noja.
じゃ、お部屋に戻ろうかのう。よいしょ
Well, shall we go back to our room? Up we go.
すべての異変が見つかりました
"All anomalies have been found."
やったのじゃー！よいしょ
I did it, noja! Up we go.
おかえりー
Welcome back!
のじゃー！
Noja!
怖かったけど、怖かったけど
It was scary, it was scary, but...
無事に、無事にクリアできましたのじゃ
I safely... safely cleared it, noja.
うん
Yeah.
びっくりするやつとかね
Like those jumpscare moments...
急に、なんか暗くなるやつとかは、すごい怖かったけど
...and the sudden darkness were super scary...
楽しかった！楽しかったのじゃ！面白かった！
...but it was fun! It was fun, noja! It was interesting!
面白かったのじゃ！
It was interesting, noja!
なんか、びっくりするのはあったけど
There were some startling things, but...
間違い探し、面白かったのじゃ
the spot-the-difference gameplay was fun, noja.
覚えたら、一回覚えたらこっちのもんですのじゃ
Once you memorize them... Once you memorize them, it's a breeze, noja!
うん
Yeah.
楽しかったのじゃ！
It was fun, noja!
やったのじゃ！
I did it, noja!
また違うなんかのゲームを、やる
I'll play another game...
また違うなんかのゲームやる。うん
...I'll play another game again. Yeah.
あのさ、おぬしさ、おぬしさ
Hey, you... you guys...
あの、わしが可愛くなくなっても嫌いにならないでくれる？
Um, if I stop being cute, will you still not hate me?
わしが叫ぶときに可愛く驚けなくても
Even if I can't look cute when I scream...
可愛く驚けなくても嫌いにならないでくれるのじゃ？
Even if I can't sound cute when startled, you won't hate me, noja?
嫌いにならないでほしいのじゃ
I don't want you to hate me, noja.
人間から好かれたくて頑張って、人間が好そうなのやってるのに
I'm trying hard to be liked by humans, doing things they seem to like...
ちょっと怖すぎると、怖すぎると
but when it's a bit too scary... too scary...
怖すぎると、怖すぎるとね、どうしてもね、どうしてもね
when it's too scary, when it's too scary, no matter what, no matter what...
我を忘れてしまいますのじゃ
I end up losing myself, noja.
うーん、のじゃ
Hmm... noja.
のじゃ
Noja.
うん
Yeah.
よし
Alright.
宣伝しちゃお
Let's plug some things.
ててーん！
Ta-da!
えっと、明日は配信お休みなのじゃ！明日…
Um, tomorrow is a stream-free day, noja! Tomorrow...
お休みですが、10月の4日
It's a day off, but October 4th,
日曜日なのじゃ。日曜日の20時から
is a Sunday! From 8:00 PM on Sunday,
「あそびまわりたい」デビュー記念歌枠リレーを行いますのじゃ！
we'll hold the "Asobimawaritai" Debut Celebration Singing Relay!
うむ。20分ずつね、歌歌ってね
Yep, we'll sing for 20 minutes each.
20分ずつ歌歌ってね
Singing for 20 minutes each.
最後はね、あちちメラのチャンネルに集合してね、4人で歌うのじゃ。
At the end, we'll gather on Achichi Mela's channel and sing as a group of four.
これをね、あちちメラのTwitterでね、あの、ツイートしたの。
I tweeted about this on Achichi Mela's Twitter.
ツイートしたからね、あの、主らね、リツイートとかね、いいねとかしてほしい。
Since I tweeted it, I'd love for you guys to retweet and like it.
リツイートとかいいねとかしてほしいな。
I really hope you'll retweet and like it.
わし、すごい、8曲連続すごい頑張ったから、リツイートとかいいねしてほしいな。
I worked really hard on the 8 consecutive songs, so please retweet and like it.
してほしいのじゃ。
I really want you to.
きっとね、主らが聞きたい歌も聞けると思う。
I'm sure you'll get to hear the songs you want to hear.
「あちちメラちゃん、この歌歌わないの？」みたいな、あちちメロ…にゃにゃにゃ。
Like, "Achichi Mela, aren't you singing this song?" or... Achichi Melo... *mumble*.
あちちメラちゃん、この歌絶対歌うやろ、みたいな歌がきっとあるじゃろ？
I'm sure there's a song where you think, "Achichi Mela is definitely going to sing this!" right?
それをね、歌うので。そう、それを歌うので、
Because I'll be singing that. Yes, I'll be singing that,
聞いてほしい。楽しみにしててほしいのじゃ。
so please listen to it. I want you to look forward to it.
ちょ、ゴールドフィンガーね、多分あれ、元曲がね、海外の曲じゃからね、ちょっと難しい気がするのじゃ。
About "Goldfinger," the original is a foreign song, so I think it might be a bit difficult.
うん、もちろん存じ上げてるんじゃが、いかんせんね、そう、海外曲じゃからのう。
Yes, of course I know it, but as expected, it is a foreign song, after all.
あ！あとね！あとね！あとね！あとね！あとね！あとね！
Ah! Also! Also! Also! Also! Also! Also!
あの、何じゃっけ、ボイス！ボイス、ボイス、ボイス！
Um, what was it... Voice! Voice, voice, voice!
ハロウィンボイス出たのじゃ！YouTubeのコミュニティに詳細があるのじゃ！ハロウィンボイス！
The Halloween Voice is out! There are details in the YouTube community tab! Halloween Voice!
わしは色欲担当！
I'm in charge of "Lust"!
ハロウィンボイス聞いてほしいのじゃ。
I want you to listen to my Halloween Voice.
頑張って撮ったのじゃ。初めてのボイス。
I worked hard on recording it. It's my very first voice pack.
きっとドキドキしちゃうと思うのじゃ。うん、聞いてほしいのじゃ。
I'm sure it'll make your heart race. Yeah, I want you to listen to it.
うん。そちらも、そちらもね、あの、Twitterとかにも情報があるので、
Yes, information on that is also available on my Twitter and other places,
おねがいしますのじゃ。
so please check it out.
あの、販売ページにサンプル？サンプルもあるから、サンプルをちょっと聞いて、続きが聞きたかったら、ゲットするでもいいと思いますのじゃ。うん。
There's a sample on the store page, so you can listen to that first. If you want to hear the rest, feel free to buy it. Yes.
よろしくおねがいしますのじゃ！
Thank you very much!
あ、あと明日！明日、秋葉原でね、「あそびまわりたい」のイベントがある！
Ah, and tomorrow! Tomorrow, there's an "Asobimawaritai" event in Akihabara!
明日と明後日ね、秋葉原でね、「あそびまわりたい」のね、あの、イベントがある。
Tomorrow and the day after, in Akihabara, there will be an "Asobimawaritai" event.
ボイスの感想タグは、プロフィール、Twitterのプロフィールにあるんじゃが、「#あちちめら」だっけ？でお願いしますのじゃ。
The hashtag for voice pack feedback is on my Twitter profile, but is it "#Achichimera"? Please use that.
「あそびまわりたい」のイベントがありますのじゃ。ショッパー？
The "Asobimawaritai" event is happening! A shopper bag?
なんか、ほら、コミケとかでもらえるさ、ショッパーあるじゃん、紙袋。あれがもらえる！
You know, like the shopping bags you get at Comiket, paper bags. You can get one of those!
「あそびまわりたい」版の、あれがもらえるのじゃ！無料！
You can get the "Asobimawaritai" version of that paper bag! For free!
あと、スタンプラリーがあって、スタンプラリーやると、無料でなんか、何だっけ、洗濯ネット？洗濯ネットもらえるっぽい。
And there's also a stamp rally. If you complete it, you can get a free laundry net, I think.
「あそびまわりたい」の絵が入ったやつ。
One with "Asobimawaritai" art on it.
すごいやろ？お楽しみに。
Isn't that amazing? Look forward to it.
行けない地方民は、あちちメラのハロウィンボイス、そしてスターティングボイスを聞くのじゃ。うん。
For those living in other regions who can't go, listen to Achichi Mela's Halloween and Starting Voice packs instead!
ボイスを聞いて、わしのことを考えるのじゃ。
Listen to my voice and think of me.
そう、洗濯ネット兼ポーチらしいのじゃ。なぜ洗濯ネット？
Right, apparently it's a laundry net slash pouch. Why a laundry net?
「あそびまわりたい」のコンセプトがコインランドリーじゃからな、気がするのじゃ。うん。コインランドリーだから。
I feel like it's because the concept of "Asobimawaritai" is a coin laundry. Yeah, because of coin laundry.
遠い主らはボイスを聞くのじゃ。ハロウィンボイスを聞いて。コスプレした、そう、わしコスプレしたのじゃ。コスプレしたわしのボイスを聞くのじゃ。
My distant viewers, please listen to the voice packs. Listen to my Halloween Voice. I did a cosplay, yes, I cosplayed! Please listen to my cosplayed voice.
明日は配信お休みじゃから、アーカイブを見直したり、となんじゃ？
Since I have no stream tomorrow, how about rewatching the archives or something?
「歌ってみた」とかね。「歌ってみた」とかを聞いてください。聞いてほしいのじゃ！
Or "Utattemita" (song covers). Please listen to my covers. I want you to listen to them!
コスプレボイス、ヴァンパイアのコスプレしたのじゃ。うん。
For the cosplay voice pack, I cosplayed as a vampire. Yes.
ので聞いてくださいのじゃ。
So please listen to it!
はい！
Yes!
じゃ、今日はおしまい。今日はおしまいですのじゃ。
Alright, that's all for today. Today's stream is ending.
主ら、1週間お疲れ様！まあ、土日もお仕事の人もきっといるじゃろうけど、
Everyone, thank you for your hard work this week! Well, some of you might have to work on weekends too,
平日お仕事、学校だった主らお疲れ様。1週間お疲れ様なのじゃ。
but to those who had work or school on weekdays, good job. Thank you for your hard work this week.
また、次は日曜日かな？
See you next on... Sunday, I guess?
日曜日に、えーと、「あそびまわりたい」の歌枠リレーで！
On Sunday, um, at the "Asobimawaritai" Singing Relay!
お会いできたら嬉しいですのじゃ。
I'd be happy if we could meet.
20時からだからね、勘違いしないように。いつも10時じゃけど。
It starts at 8:00 PM, so don't get confused. Even though it's usually at 10:00.
20時からやるので、よろしくお願いしますのじゃ！
It'll be at 8:00 PM, so please look forward to it!
今日の配信もおしまいなのじゃ。
Today's stream is also coming to an end.
最後の挨拶は「さらばじゃー」でおねがいしますのじゃ。
For our final greeting, please say "Farewell!"
お主ら行くよ！
Are you guys ready?
さらばじゃー！
Farewell!
ご視聴感謝なのじゃ！
[On-screen: Thank you for watching!]